<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
  <title>Morning Offering (Unofficial RSS)</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/</link>
  <description>Unofficial, personal-use RSS feed created from morningoffering.com daily page.</description>
  <language>en-us</language>
  <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 06:34:54 -0400</lastBuildDate>
  <item>
  <title>Morning Offering for October 16, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/10-16/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">c458ea8dd0e84c99330e17abb86daa9d10b722f4</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"The sacred heart of Christ is an inexhaustible fountain, and its sole desire is to pour itself out into the hearts of the humble so as to free them and prepare them to lead lives according to his good pleasure." <strong>St. Margaret Mary </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“If meekness is not exactly the worldly ideal, neither is it universally correlated with strength. Contrariwise, is not the first connotation of meekness in many minds that of supineness, spiritlessness, weakness? It is strange that this should be so, when Jesus set forth meekness as the expression of His own divine-human heart. It is interesting that Christ asked us to master only one lesson plan in life: “Learn of me, because I am meek, and humble of heart” (Matt. 11:29). It is certainly not without significance that He never specifically asked us to learn anything else.”<br/>
—Mother Francis, PCC, p.26</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"Then they will hand you over to persecution, and they will kill you. You will be hated by all nations because of my name. And then many will be led into sin; they will betray and hate one another. Many false prophets will arise and deceive many; and because of the increase of evildoing, the love of many will grow cold. But the one who perseveres to the end will be saved. And this gospel of the kingdom will be preached throughout the world as a witness to all nations, and then the end will come." <strong>Matthew 24:9-14</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Margaret Mary" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4308.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Margaret Mary</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Margaret Mary Alacoque (1647-1690) was born in France to a virtuous and distinguished family. As a child she showed great devotion to Jesus in the Blessed Sacrament, and by the age of 9 was practicing severe penances. In her childhood she became sick with rheumatic fever and was confined to bed for four years. She made a vow to the Blessed Virgin to consecrate herself to the religious life, after which she was instantly healed. She often had visions of Jesus, which she thought was a normal experience in the spiritual life. When she turned 17 her mother insisted that she establish a place for herself in the world. Margaret imagined that her childhood vow was not binding, and persuaded herself that she could serve God while living at home and continuing her penances and charity to the poor. She then joined her brothers at dances and began considering marriage. One day, upon returning home from a carnival ball, Jesus appeared to her and reproached her for her infidelity, reminding her of her promise. Margaret then entered a Visitation convent at the age of 24. Jesus appeared to her frequently, and entrusted to her the mission of establishing devotion to his Sacred Heart during a time when religion in France had grown rigorous and cold. Because of her visions she was greatly persecuted by those around her, until her virtue under suffering won over her enemies. Her visions were determined to be genuine and officially recognized by the Catholic Church 75 years after her death. Her feast day is October 16th.   </p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> the Holy Rosary</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Catholic Church designates October as the Month of the Holy Rosary. During this month the faithful venerate the Blessed Virgin Mary especially under her title of Our Lady of the Rosary, and make special effort to honor the Holy Rosary with group recitations and rosary processions. St. Dominic de Guzman, the founder of the Order of Preachers, is the saint to whom Our Lady famously appeared and gave the prayers of the Holy Rosary to assist him as a spiritual weapon in combating heresy and leading souls back to the one, true Catholic faith.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the the Holy Rosary" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4965.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for October 15, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/10-15/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">bd7489fb842d04673c06d1028dfc04b12fd310f0</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"Let nothing disturb you, let nothing frighten you. All things pass. God does not change. Patience achieves everything. Whoever has God lacks nothing; God alone suffices." <strong>St. Teresa of Avila</strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Perhaps we do not know what love is, nor does this greatly surprise me. Love does not consist in great sweetness of devotion, but in a fervent determination to strive to please God in all things, in avoiding, as far as possible, all that would offend Him, and in praying for the increase of the glory and honor of His Son and for the growth of the Catholic Church.”<br/>
—St. Teresa of Avila, p. 54-55</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"If anyone thinks he is religious and does not bridle his tongue but deceives his heart, his religion is vain. Religion that is pure and undefiled before God and the Father is this: to care for orphans and widows in their affliction and to keep oneself unstained by the world." <strong>James 1:26-27</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Teresa of Avila" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4441.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Teresa of Avila</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Teresa of Avila (1515–1582), also known as St. Teresa of Jesus, was born in Spain to a large, devout, and prominent Catholic family. Fascinated with the lives of the saints taught to her by her pious parents, as children she and a brother tried to run away from home to seek martyrdom among the Moors. After an uncle found them and returned them home, they built hermitages for themselves in the family garden. At the age of 14 Teresa was plunged into sorrow upon the death of her mother; to find consolation she asked the Virgin Mary to be her new mother. When she began to exhibit worldly vanities, her father placed her in a convent to be educated with other ladies of her social class. Determined to avoid marriage, and motivated more by the need for security than love for God, at the age of twenty Teresa entered religious life as a Carmelite nun. For two decades she led what she describes as a mediocre prayer life, hindered by too much socialization with visitors. However, an intense prayer experience in her forties helped her to renounce worldly attachments and enter deeper into a life of prayer. She advanced rapidly and taught others to do the same, being encouraged by a vision of the place reserved for her in hell if she was unfaithful to God's graces. She had many profound mystical experiences for which she was often slandered and ridiculed. After the reform of her own life she worked hard to reform the laxity of many Carmelite convents, and was successful even while being greatly opposed in her efforts. She was a strong and important female figure of her era, and her great progress in the spiritual life led her to write the spiritual classics Interior Castle and The Way of Perfection. For these works St. Teresa of Avila was named the first female Doctor of the Church. Her feast day is October 15th.   </p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> the Holy Rosary</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Catholic Church designates October as the Month of the Holy Rosary. During this month the faithful venerate the Blessed Virgin Mary especially under her title of Our Lady of the Rosary, and make special effort to honor the Holy Rosary with group recitations and rosary processions. St. Dominic de Guzman, the founder of the Order of Preachers, is the saint to whom Our Lady famously appeared and gave the prayers of the Holy Rosary to assist him as a spiritual weapon in combating heresy and leading souls back to the one, true Catholic faith.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the the Holy Rosary" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4965.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for October 14, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/10-14/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">465a728e9f81b9f354fd71306ccce637b74c2d93</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"No one can make excuses, because anyone can love God; and he does not ask the soul for more than to love him, because he loves the soul, and it is his love." <strong>Blessed Angela of Foligno</strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“The vow of poverty is a generous renunciation and detachment from the heavy burden of temporal things. It is an alleviation of the spirit, it is a relief afforded to human infirmity, the liberty of a noble heart to strive after eternal and spiritual blessings. It is a satiety and abundance, in which the thirst after earthly treasures is allayed, and a sovereignty and ownership, in which a most noble enjoyment of all riches is established. All this, my daughter, and many other blessings are contained in voluntary poverty, and all this the sons of the world are ignorant and deprived of, precisely because they are lovers of earthly riches and enemies of this holy and opulent poverty.”<br/>
—Ven. Mary of Agreda, p. 85</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"We know that we belong to God, and the whole world is under the power of the evil one. We also know that the Son of God has come and has given us discernment to know the one who is true. And we are in the one who is true, in his Son Jesus Christ. He is the true God and eternal life." <strong>1 John 5:19-20</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="Pope Saint Callistus I." class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/1014_email.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">Pope Saint Callistus I.</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>Pope St. Callistus I (d. 223 A.D.) was a Roman by birth and a Christian slave. He was the servant of a fellow Christian serving in the Roman imperial household. He was entrusted with the task of managing his master’s wealth, which he used to operate a bank into which many Christians invested their money. When the bank failed due to unpaid loans, Callistus fled the city in fear of retribution. He was soon caught, and in punishment was sentenced to hard slave labor in the Sardinian mines. He eventually obtained his freedom when he and the other Christian slaves working in the mines were released, or perhaps ransomed, with special pardon from the Emperor. Callistus was later recalled to Rome by Pope Zephyrinus to serve as his deacon, top adviser, and the caretaker of the important Christian cemetery along the Appian Way. This cemetery, which now bears Callistus’ name, contains the relics of many martyrs. When Pope Zephyrinus died, Callistus was elected to the Chair of St. Peter in 217 A.D. As pope, St. Callistus was known for his leniency and forgiveness. He upheld the teaching of the Church that grave sins could be forgiven with true contrition and due penance, which was controversial at the time. He reigned for five years and died a martyr; one account holds that he was killed by an anti-Christian mob, being thrown from his house and stoned to death. His feast day is October 14th.</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> the Holy Rosary</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Catholic Church designates October as the Month of the Holy Rosary. During this month the faithful venerate the Blessed Virgin Mary especially under her title of Our Lady of the Rosary, and make special effort to honor the Holy Rosary with group recitations and rosary processions. St. Dominic de Guzman, the founder of the Order of Preachers, is the saint to whom Our Lady famously appeared and gave the prayers of the Holy Rosary to assist him as a spiritual weapon in combating heresy and leading souls back to the one, true Catholic faith.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the the Holy Rosary" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4965.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for October 13, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/10-13/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">ee221dc591a510bdd86d5ad955ab5ab1aaab967f</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"Cheerfulness prepares a glorious mind for all the noblest acts." <strong>St. Elizabeth Ann Seton </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Consider not only that God your benefactor is present but also that He acts continuously in all His creatures. And for whom is this continual action, this work of God in nature? For you. Thus, He lights you by the light of day; He nourishes you with the productions of the earth; in a word, He serves you by each one of the creatures that you use; so that it is true to say that at every moment the bounty, the wisdom and the power of God are at your service and are exercised in the world for your wants or pleasures. This conduct of God toward man should be the model of your conduct toward God. You see that the presence of God in His creatures is never idle; it acts incessantly, it preserves, it governs. Beware, then, of stopping at a sterile contemplation of God present in yourself. Add action to contemplation; to the sight of the Divine presence add the faithful accomplishment of the Divine will.”<br/>
—St. Ignatius, p. 182</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"Love is patient, love is kind. It is not jealous, [love] is not pompous, it is not inflated, it is not rude, it does not seek its own interests, it is not quick-tempered, it does not brood over injury, it does not rejoice over wrongdoing but rejoices with the truth. It bears all things, believes all things, hopes all things, endures all things. Love never fails. If there are prophecies, they will be brought to nothing; if tongues, they will cease; if knowledge, it will be brought to nothing." <strong>1 Corinthians 13:4-8</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Edward the Confessor" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3362.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Edward the Confessor</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Edward the Confessor (1003-1066 A.D.) was a prince born to the King and Queen of England. His family was exiled from the kingdom when the Danish took control of the country in 1016 A.D. Edward spent much of his life in exile, probably in Normandy. Witnessing the folly of worldly ambition, he became attracted to the life of the Church and grew in piety. When opportunity arose he was persuaded to reclaim the throne of England, which he did in 1042 as one of its last Anglo-Saxon kings. The people supported his rule, and he gained a reputation as a just king committed to the welfare of his subjects. He thwarted invasions, ended unjust taxes, and was profoundly generous to the poor. His reign was marked by peace and prosperity throughout his kingdom. He married a beautiful woman to satisfy the people's desire for a queen, but, having already made a vow of chastity, he obtained his wife's agreement to live together as brother and sister. He was buried in Westminster Abbey, which he built, and after his death many miracles were ascribed to his intercession. This lead to his canonization in 1161, and in 1163 the transferral of his body to a new tomb. This was presided over by St. Thomas Becket, the Archbishop of Canterbury, who found Edward's body to be incorrupt. Edward was called "The Confessor" to distinguish him from St. Edward the Martyr. He is buried behind the high altar in Westminster Abbey. He is the patron of kings, difficult marriages, separated spouses, and the English royal family. His feast day is October 13th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> the Holy Rosary</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Catholic Church designates October as the Month of the Holy Rosary. During this month the faithful venerate the Blessed Virgin Mary especially under her title of Our Lady of the Rosary, and make special effort to honor the Holy Rosary with group recitations and rosary processions. St. Dominic de Guzman, the founder of the Order of Preachers, is the saint to whom Our Lady famously appeared and gave the prayers of the Holy Rosary to assist him as a spiritual weapon in combating heresy and leading souls back to the one, true Catholic faith.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the the Holy Rosary" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4965.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for October 12, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/10-12/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">ccbb5805cdc4a5c197d03d9e0301434408dfade1</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"Continuously ask your guardian angel for help. Your guardian angel has to become your best friend." <strong>Blessed Carlo Acutis</strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“St. Gregory of Nyssa makes a delightful comparison when he says that we are all artists and that our souls are blank canvases that we have to fill in. The colors that we must use are the Christian virtues, and our Model is Jesus Christ, the perfect Living Image of God the Father. Just as a portrait painter who wants to do a good job places himself before his model and glances at him before making each stroke, so the Christian must always have the life and virtues of Jesus Christ before his eyes so that he may never say, think, or do the least thing that is not in harmony with his Model.”<br/>
–St. Louis Mary de Montfort, p.90</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"Let love be sincere; hate what is evil, hold on to what is good love one another with mutual affection; anticipate one another in showing honor. Do not grow slack in zeal, be fervent in spirit, serve the Lord. Rejoice in hope, endure in affliction, persevere in prayer. Contribute to the needs of the holy ones, exercise hospitality." <strong>Romans 12:9-13</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="Blessed Carlo Acutis" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4036.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">Blessed Carlo Acutis</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>“For the first time in history we will see a saint dressed in jeans, sneakers, and a sweater…” These are some of the words spoken on the occasion of the beatification of Blessed Carlo Acutis in October of 2020. Blessed Carlo was born on May 3, 1991 and grew up in Italy. He enjoyed amateur computer programing and video games. From an early age he had a great devotion to the Holy Eucharist. He researched sites of Eucharistic miracles and then created a website to categorize them. This website still exists and has also been turned into a traveling exhibition of Eucharistic Miracles which has been seen around the world. Blessed Carlo Acutis suffered from leukemia and died on October 10, 2006 at the age of 15. He is remembered for his cheerfulness and compassion for those in need. He is the patron of computer programmers and youth and was beatified on behalf of Pope Francis on October 10, 2020. His exposed relics can be viewed in Assisi. His feast day is October 12th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> the Holy Rosary</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Catholic Church designates October as the Month of the Holy Rosary. During this month the faithful venerate the Blessed Virgin Mary especially under her title of Our Lady of the Rosary, and make special effort to honor the Holy Rosary with group recitations and rosary processions. St. Dominic de Guzman, the founder of the Order of Preachers, is the saint to whom Our Lady famously appeared and gave the prayers of the Holy Rosary to assist him as a spiritual weapon in combating heresy and leading souls back to the one, true Catholic faith.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the the Holy Rosary" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4965.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for October 11, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/10-11/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">917e2b8adc5abe78b2b20f306827b864c06fb036</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"The family, founded upon marriage freely contracted, one and indissoluble, must be regarded as the natural, primary cell of human society. The interests of the family, therefore, must be taken very specially into consideration in social and economic affairs, as well as in the spheres of faith and morals. For all of these have to do with strengthening the family and assisting it in the fulfillment of its mission." <strong>John XXIII, Pacem in Terris -1963</strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Just as a family needs to eat its meals together in order to get along and be nourished, so also do we need the Eucharist in order to be nourished with Christ’s Body and Blood and to attain eternal life (John 6:53-54). The Mass is also a celebration with the extended family of the Church. Some celebrations of the Mass are extra special, such as the important feasts of Christmas and Easter…These very important communal celebrations are analogous to those large family celebrations and reunions that bring many relatives together for a special occasion. Just as family reunions are never as intimate as small family dinners, neither are the large sacramental celebrations as intimate as the daily parish Mass. Yet these different kinds of Eucharistic celebrations complement one another, just as an intimate candlelight dinner complements the wedding feast.”<br/>
– Fr. Mitch Pacwa, SJ, p.94-95</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"He who dwells in the shelter of the Most High, who abides in the shadow of the Almighty, will say to the Lord, “My refuge and my fortress; my God, in whom I trust." <strong>Psalm 91:1-2</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="Pope St. John XXIII" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4274.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">Pope St. John XXIII</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>Pope St. John XXIII (1881–1963) was the third of thirteen children born to a poor sharecropping family living in Lombardy, Italy. Desiring to serve God with his life, he entered seminary at the age of 12, and, after serving a short stint in the Italian Army, was ordained a priest in 1904. He taught apologetics and church history before being called to service as a military chaplain during the first World War.  He later served in Rome on various diplomatic assignments, rising in ecclesiastical rank as bishop and then cardinal-patriarch of Venice. An obscure pick for the Supreme Pontiff, he was unexpectedly elected the 261st Pope at the age of 76. He took the name John which had not been used in over 500 years. The papacy of this presumed "caretaker pope" was expected to be an uneventful one, however, to the surprise of all, shortly into his reign he called the Second Vatican Council. He presided over its first session but did not live to see its completion. He reigned as pope for less than five years before dying of stomach cancer. As Holy Father he had a special concern for the equal dignity of humanity, the unity of all Christians, and world peace. He broke with many of the formalities of the papacy and was affectionately called the "Good Pope", in Italian, "il Papa buono." He was canonized by Pope Francis together with Pope John Paul II in 2014. His feast day is October 11th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> the Holy Rosary</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Catholic Church designates October as the Month of the Holy Rosary. During this month the faithful venerate the Blessed Virgin Mary especially under her title of Our Lady of the Rosary, and make special effort to honor the Holy Rosary with group recitations and rosary processions. St. Dominic de Guzman, the founder of the Order of Preachers, is the saint to whom Our Lady famously appeared and gave the prayers of the Holy Rosary to assist him as a spiritual weapon in combating heresy and leading souls back to the one, true Catholic faith.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the the Holy Rosary" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4965.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for October 10, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/10-10/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">443c9fdf88bee78181c838f4f7b3accc0d8c356c</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"You can't go to heaven hating somebody. Forgive now. Be compassionate now. Be patient now. Be grateful now. Love Jesus and Mary now. Accept God's will now." <strong>Mother Angelica</strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“All our perfection consists in being conformed, united and consecrated to Jesus Christ; and therefore the most perfect of all devotions is, without any doubt, that which the most perfectly conforms, unites and consecrates us to Jesus Christ. Now, Mary being the most conformed of all creatures to Jesus Christ, it follows that, of all devotions, that which most consecrates and conforms the soul to Our Lord is devotion to His holy Mother, and that the more a soul is consecrated to Mary, the more it is consecrated to Jesus.”<br/>
—St. Louis De Montfort, p. 65</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"Know this, my dear brothers: everyone should be quick to hear, slow to speak, slow to wrath, for the wrath of a man does not accomplish the righteousness of God." <strong>James 1:19-20</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Francis Borgia" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4034.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Francis Borgia</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Francis Borgia (1510-1572) was born in Spain to a noble family, the son of a Duke. On his father's side of the family he was the great-grandson of Pope Alexander VI, one of the notorious "Borgia Popes," and on his mother's side he was the great-grandson of King Ferdinand of Aragon. Francis joined the Spanish court of King Charles V at the age of 18, married, and had 8 children. In 1539 he experienced a profound religious conversion which caused him to renounce the pomp of the royal court, yet he continued his life of public service as the Viceroy of Catalonia. He made great progress in the spiritual life, and after his father's death he became the Duke of Gandia. He built a university and invited the newly-founded Society of Jesus to work in his duchy. After the death of his wife, and after providing for his children, he joined the Jesuits in Rome and was given a prominent position in the order by St. Ignatius of Loyola. Under Francis' leadership and reforms, the Jesuits advanced to such a great extent that he is considered to be their second founder. In the years following Ignatius' death, Francis became head of the order and established Jesuit missions in multiple countries. He also counseled his missionaries in both practical strategies as well as spiritual discipline. St. Francis of Borgia was a celebrated preacher and a key figure in the Counter-Reformation movement. His feast day is October 10th.</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> the Holy Rosary</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Catholic Church designates October as the Month of the Holy Rosary. During this month the faithful venerate the Blessed Virgin Mary especially under her title of Our Lady of the Rosary, and make special effort to honor the Holy Rosary with group recitations and rosary processions. St. Dominic de Guzman, the founder of the Order of Preachers, is the saint to whom Our Lady famously appeared and gave the prayers of the Holy Rosary to assist him as a spiritual weapon in combating heresy and leading souls back to the one, true Catholic faith.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the the Holy Rosary" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4965.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for October 9, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/10-09/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">6eddbb477e44fcc3c969bea7fc4e7b85a3fadce8</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"Realize it, my brethren; —every one who breathes, high and low, educated and ignorant, young and old, man and woman, has a mission, has a work. We are not sent into this world for nothing; we are not born at random; . . . God sees every one of us; He creates every soul, He lodges it in the body, one by one, for a purpose. He needs, He deigns to need, every one of us. He has an end for each of us; we are all equal in His sight, and we are placed in our different ranks and stations, not to get what we can out of them for ourselves, but to labor in them for Him. As Christ has His work, we too have ours; as He rejoiced to do His work, we must rejoice in ours also." <strong>St. John Henry Newman</strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“O my God, you and you alone are all wise and all knowing! You know, you have determined everything that will happen to us from first to last. You have ordered things in the wisest way, and you know what will be my lot year by year until I die. You know how long I have to live. You know how I shall die. You have precisely ordained everything, sin excepted. Every event of my life is the best for me that it could be, for it comes from you. You bring me on year by year, by your wonderful Providence, from youth to age, with the most perfect wisdom, and with the most perfect love.”<br/>
—St. John Henry Cardinal Newman, p. 103</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"Let us hold unwaveringly to our confession that gives us hope, for he who made the promise is trustworthy." <strong>Hebrews 10:23</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="Saint John Henry Newman" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4250.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">Saint John Henry Newman</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>Saint John Henry Cardinal Newman (1801–1890) was the eldest of six children born to a nominal Protestant family in London, England. As a child he loved reading the Scriptures and experienced a conversion to Christianity at the age of fifteen. He became a brilliant academic, an extremely influential Oxford scholar, and an Anglican priest. He was a leader in what was called the "Oxford Movement," which argued for a revival of traditional religious practice in the Church of England. Once anti-Catholic in his religious sentiments, sentiments that were common in England, Newman was increasingly impacted by the Church Fathers and other Catholic writers. His theological views gradually aligned with the Catholic Church in opposition to Anglican doctrine. Through his continued study of Church history he became unable to remain a Protestant in good faith. He made the decision to convert to Catholicism in 1845, which exposed him to much ridicule in his academic and religious circles. Two years later he was ordained a Catholic priest in Rome. He was made Cardinal in 1879. John Henry Newman is remembered for his influential writings on theology and philosophy as well as his founding of the famous London Oratory. Newman wrote forty books and 21,000 letters, some of which had profound influence on the Second Vatican Council, making him one of the most important theologians of his day. His most famous work is his Apologia in which he defends his conversion to the truths of the Catholic Church. His feast day is October 9th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> the Holy Rosary</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Catholic Church designates October as the Month of the Holy Rosary. During this month the faithful venerate the Blessed Virgin Mary especially under her title of Our Lady of the Rosary, and make special effort to honor the Holy Rosary with group recitations and rosary processions. St. Dominic de Guzman, the founder of the Order of Preachers, is the saint to whom Our Lady famously appeared and gave the prayers of the Holy Rosary to assist him as a spiritual weapon in combating heresy and leading souls back to the one, true Catholic faith.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the the Holy Rosary" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4965.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for October 8, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/10-08/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">c0bad261c0284bbdcecb19c72a5cf4bb834097d9</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"God writes his name on the soul of every man." <strong>Archbishop Fulton Sheen</strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Now, may our God be our hope. He Who made all things is better than all things. He Who made all beautiful things is more beautiful than all of them. He Who made all mighty things is more mighty than all of them. He Who made all great things is greater than all of them. Learn to love the Creator in His creature, and the maker in what He has made.”<br/>
—Saint Augustine, p. 136</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"Beloved, let us love one another, because love is of God; everyone who loves is begotten by God and knows God. Whoever is without love does not know God, for God is love." <strong>1 John 4:7-8</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="Blessed Ambrose of Siena" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4359.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">Blessed Ambrose of Siena</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>Blessed Ambrose (1220-1286) was born in Siena, Italy, the son of a book illuminator. He was born so severely deformed that his parents could not bear the sight of him. They put their son in the care of a nurse who took the child with her to daily Mass at the Dominican church. The child, often fussy, would become calm when he was placed near the altar of relics, and would cry when he was removed. While praying at the altar, the nurse would conceal the child's hideous face with a scarf. This practice continued for a year. One day a pilgrim told the nurse to remove the baby's scarf and prophesied that the child would one day become a great man. A few days later, before the same altar, the child Ambrose stretched out his deformed limbs and pronounced the name of Jesus; from that moment he was miraculously healed into a beautiful and perfectly formed child. Blessed Ambrose grew in piety and was determined to become a Dominican friar. His family and friends opposed his plan and attempted to dissuade such a handsome and talented youth from becoming a poor friar. Ambrose overcame these obstacles and joined the Dominicans at the age of 17. He studied under St. Albert the Great along with St. Thomas Aquinas, and went on to become a preacher, teacher, missionary, diplomat, and peace-broker. His skills with diplomacy earned him the respect of kings and popes alike. His feast day is October 8th.</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> the Holy Rosary</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Catholic Church designates October as the Month of the Holy Rosary. During this month the faithful venerate the Blessed Virgin Mary especially under her title of Our Lady of the Rosary, and make special effort to honor the Holy Rosary with group recitations and rosary processions. St. Dominic de Guzman, the founder of the Order of Preachers, is the saint to whom Our Lady famously appeared and gave the prayers of the Holy Rosary to assist him as a spiritual weapon in combating heresy and leading souls back to the one, true Catholic faith.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the the Holy Rosary" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4965.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for October 7, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/10-07/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">9aeb8ed2b8743abf228e64eaece639886672732c</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"Love Our Lady and make her loved; always recite the Rosary and recite it as often as possible." <strong>Padre Pio</strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Saint John Paul II proposed another set of mysteries that many of us are now familiar with: the Mysteries of Light (Luminous Mysteries). These scenes from the Gospels fill in the gap between Christ’s childhood and His Passion with events from His public ministry…They have a distinctly sacramental character not found in the traditional fifteen mysteries. They remind us that our salvation is revealed not just in Jesus’ life two thousand years ago, but also in Baptism, Matrimony, the Eucharist, and the other sacraments.”<br/>
—Dan Burke and Connie Rossini, p. 34</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"With all prayer and supplication, pray at every opportunity in the Spirit. To that end, be watchful with all perseverance and supplication for all the holy ones." <strong>Ephesians 6:18</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Justina of Padua" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4657.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Justina of Padua</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Justina of Padua (d. 304 A.D.) was a young and pious Christian woman who dedicated her virginity to Christ. She received baptism at the hands of St. Prosdocimus, the first Bishop of Padua in Italy. At the age of sixteen she was arrested for being a Christian under the persecutions of Roman Emperor Maximinian, and was ordered to make sacrifice to the pagan gods. When she refused, she was stabbed with a sword and left to die. Overlooking the field where she was martyred is a basilica named in her honor which holds her relics, as well as those of St. Luke the Evangelist, St. Matthias the Apostle, St. Prosdocimus, and other patron saints of Padua. Her feast was the day the Catholic naval forces won victory over the Turks in the Battle of Lepanto in 1571, which increased her popularity among the faithful. St. Justina of Padua's feast day is October 7th.</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> the Holy Rosary</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Catholic Church designates October as the Month of the Holy Rosary. During this month the faithful venerate the Blessed Virgin Mary especially under her title of Our Lady of the Rosary, and make special effort to honor the Holy Rosary with group recitations and rosary processions. St. Dominic de Guzman, the founder of the Order of Preachers, is the saint to whom Our Lady famously appeared and gave the prayers of the Holy Rosary to assist him as a spiritual weapon in combating heresy and leading souls back to the one, true Catholic faith.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the the Holy Rosary" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4965.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for October 6, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/10-06/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">9c5654428fefe523508302570e22b484e030938a</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"While the world changes, the cross stands firm." <strong>St. Bruno </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Imagine yourself as a living house. God comes in to rebuild that house. At first, perhaps, you can understand what He is doing. He is getting the drains right and stopping the leaks in the roof and so on: you knew that those jobs needed doing and so you are not surprised. But presently he starts knocking the house about in a way that hurts abominably and does not seem to make sense. What on earth is He up to? The explanation is that He is building quite a different house from the one you thought of – throwing out a new wing here, putting on an extra floor there, running up towers, making courtyards. You thought you were going to be made into a decent little cottage but He is building a palace. He intends to come and live in it Himself.”<br/>
—C. S. Lewis, p. 205</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"[There is] one body and one Spirit, as you were also called to the one hope of your call; one Lord, one faith, one baptism; one God and Father of all, who is over all and through all and in all. But grace was given to each of us according to the measure of Christ’s gift." <strong>Ephesians 4:4-7</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Bruno" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4249.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Bruno</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p> St. Bruno (1030-1101) was born to a noble and prominent family in Cologne, Germany. He was well educated and excelled in his studies, and became a priest around the year 1055. He went on to direct and teach at the episcopal school at Reims for many years, earning a reputation as a learned scholar. After also serving as the chancellor of his archdiocese, he and a few companions left their positions in the diocese in order to follow a path of greater religious observance. In 1084 Bruno settled in the Chartreuse Mountains in France with a small group of scholars who, like himself, desired to become contemplative monks. This was the beginning of the Carthusian order founded by St. Bruno, combining the solitary life of hermits with the conventual life of religious observance. These alpine monks embraced a strictly disciplined life of poverty, labor, prayer, and fasting.  After living six years of strict asceticism, St. Bruno was called to Rome by the Pope, who was his former student, to assist with the troubles and controversies rocking the Church. Bruno became a close advisor to the Pope and was allowed to return to monastic life only if he remained nearby within Italy, leading Bruno to establish a second Carthusian monastery there in 1095. St. Bruno wrote many manuscripts and commentaries during his life. His feast day is celebrated on October 6th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> the Holy Rosary</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Catholic Church designates October as the Month of the Holy Rosary. During this month the faithful venerate the Blessed Virgin Mary especially under her title of Our Lady of the Rosary, and make special effort to honor the Holy Rosary with group recitations and rosary processions. St. Dominic de Guzman, the founder of the Order of Preachers, is the saint to whom Our Lady famously appeared and gave the prayers of the Holy Rosary to assist him as a spiritual weapon in combating heresy and leading souls back to the one, true Catholic faith.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the the Holy Rosary" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4965.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for October 5, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/10-05/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">470ca9ba269348568692a445c542d3635fe9c013</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"Great love can change small things into great ones, and it is only love which lends value to our actions." <strong>St. Faustina Kowalska </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“I desire trust from My creatures. Encourage souls to place great trust in My fathomless mercy. Let the weak, sinful soul have no fear to approach Me, for even if it had more sins than there are grains of sand in the world, all would be drowned in the unmeasurable depths of My mercy.”<br/>
—Jesus to St. Faustina Kowalska, (1059)</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who in his great mercy gave us a new birth to a living hope through the resurrection of Jesus Christ from the dead, to an inheritance that is imperishable, undefiled, and unfading, kept in heaven for you who by the power of God are safeguarded through faith, to a salvation that is ready to be revealed in the final time." <strong>1 Peter 1:3-5</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Maria Faustina Kowalska" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4248.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Maria Faustina Kowalska</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p> St. Maria Faustina Kowalska (1905-1938), baptized with the name Helena, was one of ten children born to a devout, peasant farming family in Poland. She grew up during the tough years leading up to and following the first World War, and received little formal education. She worked as a poor housekeeper before following her religious vocation at the age of 20, entering the Congregation of the Sisters of Our Lady of Mercy in Krakow. There she was given simple, humble jobs which hid her deep interior life. St. Faustina was graced with mystical visions and revelations from Jesus, as well as her Guardian Angel and certain saints. Jesus gave her the mission to proclaim his infinite, powerful, loving mercy to the whole world, especially to hardened sinners and those facing the hour of their death. St. Faustina, as Jesus' "secretary and apostle of Divine Mercy", faithfully recorded these messages in great detail in a nearly 700-page diary. In it she promoted devotion to the Divine Mercy of Jesus Christ as instructed by Our Lord himself, now famous throughout the Church, and a great consolation for many souls who would otherwise fear to approach God because of their burden of sin. She died at the age of 33 from tuberculosis. Pope St. John Paul II made St. Faustina the first saint of the new millennium. Her feast day is October 5th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> the Holy Rosary</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Catholic Church designates October as the Month of the Holy Rosary. During this month the faithful venerate the Blessed Virgin Mary especially under her title of Our Lady of the Rosary, and make special effort to honor the Holy Rosary with group recitations and rosary processions. St. Dominic de Guzman, the founder of the Order of Preachers, is the saint to whom Our Lady famously appeared and gave the prayers of the Holy Rosary to assist him as a spiritual weapon in combating heresy and leading souls back to the one, true Catholic faith.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the the Holy Rosary" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4965.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for October 4, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/10-04/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">99516c9e228ba004e20090cd6a95b0a6ebb756a8</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"Start by doing what is necessary; then do what is possible; and suddenly you are doing the impossible." <strong>St. Francis of Assisi </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Furthermore, let us produce worthy fruits of penance. Let us also love our neighbors as ourselves. Let us have charity and humility. Let us give alms because these cleanse our souls from the stains of sin. Men lose all the material things they leave behind them in this world, but they carry with them the reward of their charity and the alms they give. For these they will receive from the Lord the reward and recompense they deserve. We must not be wise and prudent according to the flesh. Rather we must be simple, humble and pure. We should never desire to be over others. Instead, we ought to be servants who are submissive to every human being for God’s sake. The Spirit of the Lord will rest on all who live in this way and persevere in it to the end. He will permanently dwell in them. They will be the Father’s children who do his work. They are the spouses, brothers and mothers of our Lord Jesus Christ.”<br/>
—St. Francis of Assisi, p. 333</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"He said to them, "Go into the whole world and proclaim the gospel to every creature. Whoever believes and is baptized will be saved; whoever does not believe will be condemned."" <strong>Mark 16:15-16</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Francis of Assisi" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3724.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Francis of Assisi</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Francis (1181-1226) was born in Assisi, Italy, to a wealthy cloth merchant. He was a spoiled child given to pleasure, fine dress, liberal spending, and worldliness. Handsome and courteous, he was a favorite among the nobility. As a chivalrous young knight he took part in a battle between the Italian city-states and became a prisoner of war in Perugia. After his release he became seriously ill, and while reflecting on his wanton life he had a profound conversion experience. He gave up his frivolous life, cut off his family ties, and embraced a life of extreme penance and poverty in such a dramatic manner that it caused many to think he had gone mad. While praying before a crucifix in the church of San Damiano in Assisi he received a call from Christ to rebuild the Church, “which had fallen into ruin.” St. Francis followed Christ in a radical manner by patterning his new life after the example of the Apostles in the most literal way possible: he dressed as a poor peasant, worked odd jobs for food, and went through the countryside preaching repentance, love of Jesus, and peace. His joyful, radical way of life attracted followers, and with them he founded the Order of Friars Minor and the Poor Clares. His order was approved by the Holy See in 1210 and grew rapidly. Two years before his death he became the first known saint to receive the stigmata. His holiness was so widely attested that only two years after his death the Church proclaimed him a saint. St. Francis of Assisi is the patron saint of peace, ecology, the environment, animals, Italy, merchants, and families. His feast day is October 4th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> the Holy Rosary</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Catholic Church designates October as the Month of the Holy Rosary. During this month the faithful venerate the Blessed Virgin Mary especially under her title of Our Lady of the Rosary, and make special effort to honor the Holy Rosary with group recitations and rosary processions. St. Dominic de Guzman, the founder of the Order of Preachers, is the saint to whom Our Lady famously appeared and gave the prayers of the Holy Rosary to assist him as a spiritual weapon in combating heresy and leading souls back to the one, true Catholic faith.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the the Holy Rosary" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4965.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for October 3, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/10-03/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">b7f5a206964d6c8ca0043b9c381a361fff8b3a1b</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"At each step we can admire the grandeur, the power, the goodness of God. How bountifully He provides for all our wants—I would even say for our pleasures!" <strong>St. Theodore Guerin </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Infinite grief I wish from My creature in two ways: in one way, through her sorrow for her own sins, which she has committed against Me her Creator; in the other way, through her sorrow for the sins which she sees her neighbors commit against Me. Of such as these, inasmuch as they have infinite desire, that is, are joined to Me by an affection of love, and therefore grieve when they offend Me, or see Me offended, their every pain, whether spiritual or corporeal, from wherever it may come, receives infinite merit, and satisfies for a guilt which deserved an infinite penalty, although their works are finite and done in finite time; but, inasmuch as they possess the virtue of desire, and sustain their suffering with desire, and contrition, and infinite displeasure against their guilt, their pain is held worthy. Paul explained this when he said: If I had the tongues of angels, and if I knew the things of the future and gave my body to be burned, and have not love, it would be worth nothing to me. The glorious Apostle thus shows that finite works are not valid, either as punishment or recompense, without the condiment of the affection of love.”<br/>
—St. Catherine of Siena, p. 4</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"What will separate us from the love of Christ? Will anguish, or distress, or persecution, or famine, or nakedness, or peril, or the sword? As it is written: "For your sake we are being slain all the day; we are looked upon as sheep to be slaughtered." No, in all these things we conquer overwhelmingly through him who loved us." <strong>Romans 8:35-37</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Theodore Guerin" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3881.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Theodore Guerin</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Theodore Guerin (1798–1856), also known as St. Theodora, was born in Etables, France, towards the end of the French Revolution. She was a pious child who loved prayer and who knew her vocation was to be a nun. However, she was delayed in following this path after the murder of her father when she was 15, which, in addition to the previous death of two of her siblings, sent her mother into a deep depression. St. Theodore took on the household tasks and the care of her mother and her remaining sister. Finally, when she was 25, her mother gave her consent, and Theodore left home to enter the religious life. She joined the Sisters of Providence who served God by educating children and caring for the poor, the sick, and the dying. In 1840 she was asked to lead a band of missionary sisters and establish her order in the United States of America, specifically to serve the pioneers in Indiana. Even though her health was fragile, she crossed the Atlantic and then traveled by steamboat and stagecoach until she reached the wilderness mission of St. Mary of the Woods, which consisted only of a tiny log chapel. She and her five sisters endured the extreme hardships common to life on the frontier. Less than a year after arriving she opened an academy which became the first Catholic women's Liberal Arts college in the United States, still active today, called St. Mary of the Woods College. St. Theodore also established numerous schools, pharmacies, and orphanages throughout the state of Indiana. She was beatified by Pope John Paul II and canonized in 2006 by Pope Benedict XVI. Her feast day is October 3rd.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> the Holy Rosary</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Catholic Church designates October as the Month of the Holy Rosary. During this month the faithful venerate the Blessed Virgin Mary especially under her title of Our Lady of the Rosary, and make special effort to honor the Holy Rosary with group recitations and rosary processions. St. Dominic de Guzman, the founder of the Order of Preachers, is the saint to whom Our Lady famously appeared and gave the prayers of the Holy Rosary to assist him as a spiritual weapon in combating heresy and leading souls back to the one, true Catholic faith.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the the Holy Rosary" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4965.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for October 2, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/10-02/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">1edabe9d0ca674d41c7477433c70de33f0e88141</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"Make friends with the angels, who though invisible are always with you. Often invoke them, constantly praise them, and make good use of their help and assistance in all your temporal and spiritual affairs." <strong>St. Francis de Sales </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“St. Luke tells us that “there appeared to Him [in the Garden of Gethsemane]  an angel from heaven to strengthen him” (22:43). It was an angel in human form, as the expression used by St. Luke indicates an apparition visible to bodily eyes. An angel announced Christ’s coming into the world, a choir of angels proclaimed His birth, and after the temptation in the desert, angels came to minister to Him. The angels who ministered to Jesus came to assist Him after the trial of the forty days’ fast and the temptation. In Gethsemane an angel appeared in order to strengthen Him in advance for the awful climax of His mental anguish in the agony and bloody sweat. Jesus’ sufferings were concentrated in His soul, but from the soul they overflowed to the body, distressing and weakening it. It is likely, therefore, that the angel brought Jesus strength for both soul and body.”<br/>
—Fr. Ralph Gorman, C.P.</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"The Lord has established his throne in the heavens, and his kingdom rules over all. Bless the Lord, O you his angels, you mighty ones who do his word, hearkening to the voice of his word! Bless the Lord, all his hosts,
his ministers that do his will!" <strong>Psalm 103:19-21</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="Guardian Angels" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3880.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">Guardian Angels</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p> October 2nd is the Feast of the Guardian Angels. Although Guardian Angels have been venerated since the early days of the Church, it wasn’t until the 17th century that Pope Clement X extended their feast day to the Universal Church. Although not a dogmatic article of the faith, it is a firmly established Catholic belief that each individual human being has their own Guardian Angel assigned to them by God to watch over their soul, help them avoid sin and temptation, and lead them to heaven, taken in part from Jesus' words in the Gospel of Matthew: "See that you do not despise one of these little ones, for I say to you that their angels in heaven always look upon the face of my heavenly Father." The Church thanks God for our heavenly helpers, the Guardian Angels, who minister to us in our need and guide us on the path of salvation.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> the Holy Rosary</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Catholic Church designates October as the Month of the Holy Rosary. During this month the faithful venerate the Blessed Virgin Mary especially under her title of Our Lady of the Rosary, and make special effort to honor the Holy Rosary with group recitations and rosary processions. St. Dominic de Guzman, the founder of the Order of Preachers, is the saint to whom Our Lady famously appeared and gave the prayers of the Holy Rosary to assist him as a spiritual weapon in combating heresy and leading souls back to the one, true Catholic faith.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the the Holy Rosary" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4965.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for October 1, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/10-01/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">1d7b26ec7e9d40ce515a811e8e4cfb32f571c77d</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"A word or a smile is often enough to put fresh life in a despondent soul." <strong>St. Therese of Lisieux </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Prayer, for me, is simply a raising of the heart, a simple glance towards Heaven, an expression of love and gratitude in the midst of trial, as well as in times of joy; in a word, it is something noble and supernatural expanding my soul and uniting it to God. Whenever my soul is so dry that I am incapable of a single good thought, I always say an Our Father or a Hail Mary very slowly, and these prayers alone cheer me up and nourish my soul with divine food.”<br/>
—St. Therese of Lisieux, p. 141</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"I urge you therefore, brothers, by the mercies of God, to offer your bodies as a living sacrifice, holy and pleasing to God, your spiritual worship. Do not conform yourselves to this age but be transformed by the renewal of your mind, that you may discern what is the will of God, what is good and pleasing and perfect." <strong>Romans 12:1-2</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Therese of Lisieux" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3723.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Therese of Lisieux</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p> St. Therese of Lisieux (1873-1897) was the last of nine children born to Saints Louis and Zelie Martin in Alencon, France. Her family was devoutly religious, and all five surviving siblings, all daughters, entered the convent. From an early age Therese desired to give herself totally to Jesus. Her happy childhood gave way to trial following the death of her mother when she was four years old. This event changed her personality from merry and bright to withdrawn and sensitive. She also suffered a strange illness that brought her near death. Her sisters prayed for her recovery, and Therese was completely healed after she saw the Virgin Mary statue in her room smile down on her. Just before her 14th birthday, on Christmas Eve, Therese had a mystical experience of the Child Jesus. Her sensitiveness disappeared and her faith was greatly fortified. She attended daily Mass with her father and cultivated her strong desire for the salvation of souls. At the age of 15 she obtained special permission to enter the Carmelite convent in Lisieux where two of her sisters were professed. Recognizing her youth and weakness, and unable to do the great things for God in the world that her heart desired, she determined that she would follow the path of spiritual childhood at the feet of Jesus, as his "Little Flower", and instead focus on small acts of kindness for love of Jesus and interior acts of self-denial, a spirituality called "The Little Way."  Therese died of Tuberculosis at the age of 24, and her high degree of holiness was discovered through her autobiography, Story of a Soul. Her "Little Way" became profoundly influential around the world, and although she was not a learned scholar, her deep theological life caused Pope St. John Paul II to declare her a Doctor of the Church. She is the patron against sickness, tuberculosis, and loss of parents, as well as of pilots, air crews, florists, missionaries, and the sick. St. Therese of Lisieux's feast day is October 1st.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> the Holy Rosary</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Catholic Church designates October as the Month of the Holy Rosary. During this month the faithful venerate the Blessed Virgin Mary especially under her title of Our Lady of the Rosary, and make special effort to honor the Holy Rosary with group recitations and rosary processions. St. Dominic de Guzman, the founder of the Order of Preachers, is the saint to whom Our Lady famously appeared and gave the prayers of the Holy Rosary to assist him as a spiritual weapon in combating heresy and leading souls back to the one, true Catholic faith.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the the Holy Rosary" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4965.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 30, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-30/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">926fb452bdf7dcf82c4c2d31a39e58b10c392ecf</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"God loves those who thank Him even in suffering." <strong>St. Arnold Janssen </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Chastity is the most unpopular of the Christian virtues. There is no getting away from it; the Christian rule is, ‘Either marriage, with complete faithfulness to your partner, or else total abstinence.’ Now this is so difficult and so contrary to our instincts, that obviously either Christianity is wrong or our sexual instinct, as it now is, has gone wrong. One or the other. Of course, being a Christian, I think it is the instinct which has gone wrong … God knows our situation; He will not judge us as if we had no difficulties to overcome. What matters is the sincerity and perseverance of our will to overcome them. Before we can be cured we must want to be cured. Those who really wish for help will get it; but for many modern people even the wish is difficult … We may, indeed, be sure that perfect chastity—like perfect charity—will not be attained by any merely human efforts. You must ask for God’s help. Even when you have done so, it may seem to you for a long time that no help, or less help than you need, is being given. Never mind. After each failure, ask forgiveness, pick yourself up and try again. Very often what God first helps us towards is not the virtue itself but just this power of always trying again. For however important chastity (or courage, or truthfulness, or any other virtue) may be, this process trains us in habits of the soul which are more important still. It cures our illusions about ourselves and teaches us to depend on God. We learn, on the one hand, that we cannot trust ourselves even in our best moments, and, on the other, that we need not despair even in our worst, for our failures are forgiven. The only fatal thing is to sit down content with anything less than perfection.”<br/>
—C. S. Lewis, p. 95</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"It is he who made the earth by his power, who established the world by his wisdom, and by his understanding stretched out the heavens." <strong>Jeremiah 10:12</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Jerome" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3684.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Jerome</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p> St. Jerome (347 – 420) was born to a wealthy pagan family in Dalmatia. He was sent to Rome for his schooling and there converted to Christianity, being baptized by Pope Liberius. He studied theology and traveled widely to the important intellectual and theological centers across the newly-established Christian Empire. He was ordained a priest at Antioch and lived many years as a hermit in a nearby desert. He became an extraordinary scholar, considered to be the most learned of the Latin Church Fathers.  Because of his many significant theological works, most notably the thirty years he spent writing the Latin translation of the Bible (the Latin Vulgate), he is one of the most influential and orthodox theologians in the life of the early Church. In his final years Saint Jerome lived in a monastery that he founded in the Holy Land near Bethlehem, where he worked on writing histories and biographies in addition to drawing deeper into a life of prayer and asceticism. For his important scholarly contributions St. Jerome was named a Doctor of the Church. He is the patron of libraries, archaeologists, students, and translators. St. Jerome's feast day is September 30th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 29, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-29/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">879b5ffd7d8567054324e394a8aa72a983348162</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"When you awake in the night, transport yourself quickly in spirit before the Tabernacle, saying: 'Behold, my God, I come to adore You, to praise, thank, and love you, and to keep you company with all the Angels.'" <strong>St. John Vianney </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“With regard to the nobility of the angels, we need only consider that they possess a privileged place amongst all the creations of God. For they are of a purely spiritual substance and of an immortal nature, immune from the sufferings, disease, aging, and death to which corporeal beings are all subject. Their intelligence is such that they are free from all errors and ignorance with respect to knowledge of created things. In addition to this perfectly illuminated light of intelligence, the angels possess a will which is completely and utterly constant, such that it may not be overcome or made to waver by any perturbation or adversity.”<br/>
–St. Aloysius Gonzaga, p.32</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"For he will give his angels charge of you to guard you in all your ways. On their hands they will bear you up, lest you dash your foot against a stone." <strong>Psalm 91:11-12</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="Archangels" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3683.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">Archangels</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>The Archangels St. Gabriel, St. Michael, and St. Raphael share a feast day on September 29th. These are the only three angels mentioned by name in Sacred Scripture.  St. Gabriel means “Power of God." He is the messenger or herald angel most famous for appearing to the Blessed Virgin Mary at the Annunciation (Luke 1:11-38).  St. Michael means “Who is like God?" He is the warrior angel, the famous foe of Satan, who is the champion of God’s people and guardian and protector of the Church (Rev. 12:7-9).  St. Raphael means “God has healed." He is a companion and healing angel, most famous for curing a man's blindness and for traveling with Tobiah in the book of Tobit (Tob. 12).</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 28, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-28/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">0032b0a00861b481fff6fc1d615b314bbcc078ec</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"Let us make up for lost time. Let us give to God the time that remains to us." <strong>St. Alphonsus Liguori </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Suppress Interior Noise – God created your soul silent and keeps it inviolate at baptism. He filled it with Himself, nothing other than Himself. It is later, little by little that the world bursts in. Noise invades, covering the soft voice of God. Since then, the racket amplifies itself. Return to your baptismal silence, my brother! Noise has three generators: memories, curiosity, and worries. Paralyze their action.”<br/>
— An Anonymous Carthusian Monk</p><p> </p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"I, then, a prisoner for the Lord, urge you to live in a manner worthy of the call you have received, with all humility and gentleness, with patience, bearing with one another through love, striving to preserve the unity of the spirit through the bond of peace." <strong>Ephesians 4:1-3</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Wenceslaus" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3722.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Wenceslaus</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Wenceslaus (907–935 A.D.) was the son of the Duke of Bohemia. His grandfather was converted to Christianity by the missionaries Sts. Cyril and Methodius. His mother, Dragomir, was the daughter of a pagan tribal chief who was baptized at her marriage. After the death of his father, Wenceslaus received a Christian upbringing from his grandmother, St. Ludmila, while his mother reverted to her pagan ways. Dragomir reigned as regent, had St. Ludmila killed, and worked to oppose the spread of Christianity in Bohemia. When St. Wenceslaus was 18 he took control of the government and exiled his mother. St. Wenceslaus was described as a pious, humble, and intelligent ruler who worked to established Christianity in the land that would become part of the Holy Roman Empire. He was known for his vow of virginity, his many virtues, and his life of prayer and good works. After a political dispute arose, his mother and his younger brother, called Boleslaus the Cruel, plotted his murder along with a group of disaffected nobles. Boleslaus invited his brother to celebrate the feast of Sts. Cosmas and Damian, and arranged to have him assassinated on his way to Mass. St. Wenceslaus muttered words of forgiveness as he died, and his body was buried at the murder site. His brother succeeded him as Duke of Bohemia. Three years later Boleslaus repented of his crime, and had his brother's remains transferred to the Church of St. Vitus in Prague. Wenceslaus was considered a saint by the people at the time of his death. His feast day is September 28th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 27, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-27/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">afd77e0a87323243d6cba63395b3478ded686c03</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"We should strive to keep our hearts open to the sufferings and wretchedness of other people, and pray continually that God may grant us that spirit of compassion which is truly the spirit of God." <strong>St. Vincent de Paul </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Let us beware of complaints, resentments, and evil-speaking against those who are ill-disposed to us, discontented with us, or hostile to our plans and arrangements, or who even persecute us with injuries, insults, and calumnies. Rather let us go on treating them as cordially as at first, or more so, as far as possible showing them esteem, always speaking well of them, doing them good, serving them on occasion, even to the point of taking shame and disgrace upon ourselves, if necessary to save their honor. All this ought to be done, first, to overcome evil with good, according to the teaching of the Apostles; and secondly, because they are our allies rather than our adversaries, as they aid us to destroy self-love, which is our greatest foe; and since it is they who give us an opportunity to gain merit, they ought to be considered our dearest friends.”<br/>
—St. Vincent de Paul, p.413</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"Whoever loves me will keep my word, and my Father will love him, and we will come to him and make our dwelling with him. Whoever does not love me does not keep my words; yet the word you hear is not mine but that of the Father who sent me." <strong>John 14:23-24</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Vincent de Paul" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4358.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Vincent de Paul</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Vincent de Paul (1581–1660) was born in France to a peasant farming family. As a child he grew up herding sheep, and showed such an aptitude for his studies that his father sold the family oxen to fund his seminary education. After his ordination in 1600, St. Vincent worked in Toulouse as a tutor to pay for his doctorate. In 1605, while traveling by sea, he was captured by Turkish pirates. He was taken to Tunis in Africa and sold into slavery four times before escaping in 1607 along with his master, whom he had coverted to the faith. St. Vincent then continued his studies in Rome, and afterwards returned to France. He served as a parish priest and ministered to the nobility; however, two life-changing encounters with destitute people inspired him to begin work among the poor and marginalized. He gathered the wealthy women of his parish to collect funds for missionary projects. From this group came the Daughters of Charity of St. Vincent de Paul. He also founded an Order of priests, the Vincentians, who, during a time of general laxity and ignorance among the clergy, devoted themselves to the Evangelical Councils while serving in small towns and villages. He committed himself to the education of priests and conducted many retreats for their spiritual formation. He also ministered to convicts suffering deplorable conditions in prison, and won many to the faith in addition to building them a hospital. St. Vincent renewed the faith of France during a time of spiritual crisis. For this he was named the patron of charitable works. He is also the patron of the St. Vincent de Paul Society, an organization dedicated to the service of the poor, now working in 132 countries. His feast day is September 27th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 26, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-26/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">d0003f385e852e7439b5df71caa123754fe7cc29</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"Holiness consists simply in doing God's will, and being just what God wants us to be." <strong>St. Therese of Lisieux - The Little Flower </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Through the sacraments of Christian initiation, man receives the new life of Christ. Now we carry this life ‘in earthen vessels’, and it remains ‘hidden with Christ in God’. We are still in our ‘earthly tent’, subject to suffering, illness, and death. This new life as a child of God can be weakened and even lost by sin. The Lord Jesus Christ, physician of our souls and bodies, who forgave the sins of the paralytic and restored him to bodily health, has willed that his Church continue, in the power of the Holy Spirit, his work of healing and salvation, even among her own members. This is the purpose of the two sacraments of healing: the sacrament of Penance and the sacrament of Anointing of the Sick.”<br/>
—The Catechism of the Catholic Church, 1420-21</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"Commit your way to the Lord; trust in him, and he will act. He will bring forth your vindication as the light, and your right as the noonday. Be still before the Lord, and wait patiently for him; fret not yourself over him who prospers in his way, over the man who carries out evil devices!" <strong>Psalm 37:5-7</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="Sts. Cosmas &amp; Damian" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4357.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">Sts. Cosmas &amp; Damian</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>Sts. Cosmas and Damian (d. 287 A.D.) were twin brothers born in Arabia. They both became skilled physicians who practiced in Asia Minor. They took no money for their medical services, for which they were well-respected. Because of their charity they drew many to the Catholic faith. During the Christian persecution under the Roman Emperor Diocletian, Cosmas and Damian were targeted, arrested, and tortured. After being miraculously preserved from injury throughout their cruel tortures, holding firm in their faith to the end, they were finally killed by beheading. They were martyred together with their three brothers. Their remains were buried in Syria and many miracles were attributed to them. In gratitude for the healing he received through the intercession of Sts. Cosmas and Damian, Roman Emperor Justinian I (6th c.) restored a church dedicated to their honor in Constantinople, which became a place of pilgrimage. Sts. Cosmas and Damian are regarded as the patron saints of physicians, surgeons, and pharmacists. They are mentioned by name in the Roman Canon of the Mass, and share a feast day on September 26th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 25, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-25/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">cbf5a9a446d737ef62f051f954145a8a1cf88d5a</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"Consider God's charity. Where else have we ever seen someone who has been offended voluntarily paying out his life for those who have offended him?" <strong>St. Catherine of Siena </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“I remind you, My daughter, that as often as you hear the clock strike the third hour, immerse yourself completely in My mercy, adoring and glorifying it; invoke its omnipotence for the whole world, and particularly for poor sinners; for at that moment mercy was opened wide for every soul. In this hour you can obtain everything for yourself and for others for the asking; it was the hour of grace for the whole world—mercy triumphed over justice. My daughter, try your best to make the Stations of the Cross in this hour, provided that your duties permit it; and if you are not able to make the Stations of the Cross, then at least step into the chapel for a moment and adore, in the Blessed Sacrament, My Heart, which is full of mercy; and should you be unable to step into the chapel, immerse yourself in prayer there where you happen to be, if only for a very brief instant.”<br/>
—Jesus to St. Faustina Kowalska, (1572)</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"So, as you received Christ Jesus the Lord, walk in him, rooted in him and built upon him and established in the faith as you were taught, abounding in thanksgiving." <strong>Colossians 2:6-7</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Cleophas" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3721.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Cleophas</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Cleophas (1st c.) was one of Jesus' seventy disciples, and one of the two disciples who were traveling along the road to Emmaus after the crucifixion and resurrection of Jesus in Jerusalem, as recounted in Luke's Gospel. The resurrected Jesus appeared and walked along the road with St. Cleophas and his companion, explaining the events of his Passion and how they fulfilled the Holy Scriptures. According to one tradition, Cleophas (also known as Alphaeus), was a relative of Jesus; he was the brother of St. Joseph, and therefore was Jesus' uncle. Cleophas was the husband of St. Mary of Cleophas, and they had three sons we know by name: St. Simon, St. James the Less, and St. Jude. St. Cleophas, through his daughter Mary Salome, was also grandfather to St. James the Greater and St. John. Therefore three of his sons and two of his grandsons were among the Twelve Apostles. According to tradition, St. Cleophas was martyred by the Jewish authorities in the same home in which he received Jesus as a guest. His feast day is September 25th.</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 24, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-24/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">07e75711ac536c49697ca83a17a050d7fc30ec86</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"The Divine Heart is an ocean full of all good things, wherein poor souls can cast all their needs; it is an ocean full of joy to drown all our sadness, an ocean of humility to drown our folly, an ocean of mercy to those in distress, an ocean of love in which to submerge our poverty." <strong>St. Margaret Mary </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“I never found anyone so religious and devout as not to have sometimes a subtraction of grace, or feel a diminution of fervor. No saint was ever so highly rapt and illuminated as not to be tempted sooner or later. For he is not worthy of the high contemplation of God who has not, for God’s sake, been exercised with some tribulation. For temptation going before is usually a sign of ensuing consolation. For heavenly comfort is promised to such as have been proved by temptation. To him that overcometh, saith our Lord, I will give to eat of the tree of life.”<br/>
—Thomas à Kempis, p. 65</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"But you, be self-possessed in all circumstances; put up with hardship; perform the work of an evangelist; fulfill your ministry. For I am already being poured out like a libation, and the time of my departure is at hand. I have competed well; I have finished the race; I have kept the faith. From now on the crown of righteousness awaits me, which the Lord, the just judge, will award to me on that day, and not only to me, but to all who have longed for his appearance." <strong>2 Timothy 4:5-8</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Gerard Sagredo" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4349.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Gerard Sagredo</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Gerard Sagredo (980–1046 A.D.) was born in Venice, Italy. From an early age he desired to dedicate his life to God, and as a young man became a Benedictine monk. He first served as abbot at a monastery in Venice, but left to make a pilgrimage to the Holy Land. While passing through Hungary he met the Hungarian king, St. Stephen, who asked him to stay in his country to evangelize and minister to his people. St. Gerard agreed, and was named Bishop of Csanád and the royal tutor of the Hungarian prince. He ministered tirelessly among the Hungarian people and helped to convert the whole country to Christianity, for which he is called the "Apostle of Hungary." After the death of King St. Stephen there was a pagan uprising against the Christians, and St. Gerard was martyred for the faith along with two others. His death took place on a hill in Budapest which is now named after him; according to one tradition he was placed in a barrel lined with spikes, and rolled down the hill. He was declared a saint in 1083 by Pope St. Gregory VII. St. Gerard Sagredo is the patron saint of Hungary, and his feast day is September 24th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 23, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-23/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">8aecaedbe40694378000e1a4825ba082657c60ee</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"You must speak to Jesus, not only with your lips, but also with your heart; actually, on certain occasions, you should speak with only your heart." <strong>Saint Padre Pio</strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Always be impartial and just in your deeds. Put yourself into your neighbor’s place, and him in yours, and then you will judge fairly . . . Frequently, therefore, examine your heart, whether it is so disposed towards your neighbor, as you would have his disposed towards you, were you to change places; for this is the true test.”<br/>
—St. Francis de Sales, p. 226</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"O give thanks to the Lord, for he is good; for his steadfast love endures forever." <strong>1 Chronicles 16:34</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Padre Pio of Pietrelcina" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4247.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Padre Pio of Pietrelcina</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Padre Pio of Pietrelcina (1887–1968) was born to peasant farmers in southern Italy. By the time he was 5 years old he practiced a life of penance and made the decision to give himself completely to God. He grew up working in the fields, and at the age of 19 joined the Capuchin Franciscan friars. His Franciscan spirituality was characterized by a life of poverty, love of nature, and charity to those in need, especially to those who were his "spiritual children." St. Padre Pio had many spiritual gifts and was a great miracle-worker. These were well-documented from multiple reliable sources and included bilocation, levitation, reading souls, and physical healing by touch. Word of his holiness spread and people both pious and curious flocked to see him, especially to have him hear their confession. He is the first priest known to have received the stigmata, for which he suffered suspicion and investigation. Because of the unusual supernatural phenomena surrounding his life, he is considered one of the great visionaries and mystics of the Church. Padre Pio died in 1968 at the age of 81. He was canonized by Pope St. John Paul II in 2002. Because of the many miracles he performed during his life, he is commonly invoked as a healing saint for various ailments. His feast day is September 23rd.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 22, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-22/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">95ed0a3b1392a68f37b67ada3d2953ad3a00fae5</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"Grant me, O Lord my God, a mind to know you, a heart to seek you, wisdom to find you, conduct pleasing to you, faithful perseverance in waiting for you, and a hope of finally embracing you." <strong>St. Thomas Aquinas </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“There is not a moment in which God does not present Himself under the cover of some pain to be endured, of some consolation to be enjoyed, or of some duty to be performed. All that takes place within us, around us, or through us, contains and conceals His divine action. It is really and truly there present, but invisibly present, so that we are always surprised and do not recognise His operation until it has ceased. If we could lift the veil, and if we were attentive and watchful God would continually reveal Himself to us, and we should see His divine action in everything that happened to us, and rejoice in it. At each successive occurrence we should exclaim: ‘It is the Lord’, and we should accept every fresh circumstance as a gift of God. We should look upon creatures as feeble tools in the hands of an able workman, and should discover easily that nothing was wanting to us, and that the constant providence of God disposed Him to bestow upon us at every moment whatever we required.”<br/>
—Fr. Jean-Pierre de Caussade, p. 49</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"The way of the righteous is level; thou dost make smooth the path of the righteous. In the path of thy judgments, O Lord, we wait for thee; thy memorial name is the desire of our soul. My soul yearns for thee in the night, my spirit within me earnestly seeks thee. For when thy judgments are in the earth, the inhabitants of the world learn righteousness." <strong>Isaiah 26:7-9</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="Saint Ignatius of Santhia" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4327.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">Saint Ignatius of Santhia</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Ignatius of Santhia (1686-1770) was born in Italy to an upper-class family. He received his early education from a devout priest, a relative of his mother, who inspired him to join the priesthood. He studied philosophy and theology, and after his ordination served as a diocesan priest for six years. St. Ignatius earned a reputation as an excellent preacher of retreats and missions, and he had a promising future within the diocese. His family and parishioners were surprised and disappointed when he decided to join the Capuchin Franciscans in Turin as a poor, humble friar. However, St. Ignatius flourished in the poverty and simplicity of the Franciscan way of life. He became well-known for his wisdom and sanctity, and many people from all walks of life came to him for confession and spiritual direction. He had a great devotion to the Blessed Virgin Mary and prayed the rosary faithfully. He served God with humble obedience and inspired this virtue in the Franciscan novices over whom he had charge. He spent his last years on a sickbed where he continued to hear confessions and give direction to his visitors. St. Ignatius of Santhia's feast day is September 22nd.</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 15, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-15/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">5cdb3e86ca2a8552804e1b0a3c7b1ecb0e214c81</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"I see clearly with the interior eye, that the sweet God loves with a pure love the creature that He has created, and has a hatred for nothing but sin, which is more opposed to Him than can be thought or imagined." <strong>St. Catherine of Genoa </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“If we have any distinct concept of blessedness connected with mourning, it could likely have been that it is a blessed thing to be rid of it. Are not mourners by widely accepted definition the unhappy ones? Obviously, if a mourner is blessed, then it has to mean that he is blessed to have gotten out of this painful predicament, to have escaped from this sorrowful situation, to have fended off suffering. And so we might well have written the third Beatitude like this: Blessed are they who enjoy the comfort of not having anything to mourn about. But then we run up against the hard fact that this is just not what Christ said…We shall have to deal with the words that our blessed Savior uttered and not with the words that we think He ought to have uttered.”<br/>
—Mother Francis, PCC, p.36</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"Make me understand the way of thy precepts, and I will meditate on thy wondrous works. My soul melts away for sorrow; strengthen me according to thy word! Put false ways far from me; and graciously teach me thy law! I have chosen the way of faithfulness, I set thy ordinances before me. I cleave to thy testimonies, O Lord; let me not be put to shame! I will run in the way of thy commandments when thou enlargest my understanding!" <strong>Psalm 119:27-32</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Catherine of Genoa" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3879.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Catherine of Genoa</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Catherine (1447–1510) was born into an aristocratic family in Genoa, Italy. She was a quiet, obedient, physically beautiful, and holy child who devoted herself to prayer and penance. At the age of 13 she made an attempt to enter a convent, but was rejected. At the age of 16 she consented to a marriage arranged by her family for political and financial gain. Her husband was faithless and violent, and their marriage was miserable. Catherine did not bear any children, and for the first five years lived as a hermit in her fine home. After this time, upon her family's rebuke of her solitude, she began to engage in the kind of social activity expected for her state in life. This only increased her weariness and depression, and led to the loss of her religious fervor. Catherine prayed earnestly for assistance in her trouble. Taking the advice of her sister, who was a nun, Catherine went to confession, and through the sacrament had a profound mystical experience in which she clearly saw the depth of her sinfulness contrasted with the depth of God's love. From that point on she renewed her commitment to rigorous prayer, penance, and works of mercy, and God continued to favor her with mystical visions. Catherine later won the conversion of her husband, and they were received into the Third Order of St. Francis. Together they cared for the poor and sick in the Genoa hospital, over which Catherine became administrator. St. Catherine's mystical visions were recorded by her confessor toward the end of her life, the most famous being her Treatise of Purgatory. Her feast day is celebrated on September 15th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 16, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-16/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">9370124272401db330dd297fcd0177549f21aad8</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"Prayer is the best armor we have, it is the key which opens the heart of God." <strong>Saint Padre Pio of Pietrelcina </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“In the case of biblical parables we must always expect that the addressees will be brought into a situation in which they believe they are going to enjoy a thrilling story—and then all at once everything changes: they are confronted with the will of God or the evil situation in which they are living in God’s eyes.”<br/>
—Gerhard Lohfink, p.17</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"If you love me, you will keep my commandments. And I will ask the Father, and he will give you another Advocate to be with you always, the Spirit of truth, which the world cannot accept, because it neither sees nor knows it. But you know it, because it remains with you, and will be in you." <strong>John 14:15-17</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="Pope St. Cornelius" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3504.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">Pope St. Cornelius</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>Pope St. Cornelius (d. 253 A.D.) was a Roman citizen and a holy priest who became the twenty-first successor to the chair of St. Peter, following a fourteen-month vacancy when Pope St. Fabian was martyred by Roman Emperor Decius. When the Emperor temporarily left Rome, the persecution against the Christians subsided long enough for the Church to elect St. Cornelius as the new Roman Pontiff. During Pope St. Cornelius' two year reign a great controversy arose as to what to do with Catholics who apostatized from the Christian faith under threat of death during the persecution. Many were being received back to the sacraments without any penance. In response to the scandal, some maintained that apostates could not be forgiven and could only be admitted back to the sacraments if they were re-baptized. Chief among them was a priest named Novatian, who, as a result of the scandal, caused a schism when he had himself consecrated as an anti-pope. In response, Pope St. Cornelius convened a synod of bishops to confirm his rightful authority as Pope. Novatian was excommunicated and his doctrine was condemned as heresy. Pope St. Cornelius proclaimed that the Church had the power and authority to forgive repentant apostasy, and that converted apostates could be readmitted to the sacraments after true contrition with adequate penance. Soon a new wave of persecution against the Christians broke out, and Pope St. Cornelius was driven into exile and martyred. His feast day is celebrated on September 16th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 17, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-17/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">ef4bf2f1ce76dc1af7106064ba05a562f31428ef</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"May the Holy Spirit enkindle you with the fire of His Love so that you may persevere, unfailingly, in the love of His service. Thus you may merit to become, at last, a living stone in the celestial Jerusalem." <strong>St. Hildegard von Bingen </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“You have never begrudged the martyrs their triumph but rather trained them for it. And so I am asking you to be consistent with the lessons you teach them. Just beg for me the courage and endurance not only to speak but also to will what is right, so that I may not only be called a Christian, but prove to be one. For if I prove myself to be a Christian by martyrdom, then people will call me one, and my loyalty to Christ will be apparent when the world sees me no more. Nothing you can see is truly good. For our Lord Jesus Christ, now that he has returned to his Father, has revealed himself more clearly. Our task is not one of producing persuasive propaganda; Christianity shows its greatness when it is hated by the world.”<br/>
—St. Ignatius of Antioch, p. 194</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"The Lord bless you and keep you; the Lord make his face to shine upon you, and be gracious to you; the Lord lift up his countenance upon you, and give you peace." <strong>Numbers 6:24-26</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Hildegard von Bingen" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3502.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Hildegard von Bingen</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p> St. Hildegard von Bingen (1098–1179) was born to a large and noble German family. She began to have mystical visions at the age of three which continued throughout her life. Her parents, promising her to the service of God, sent her to be educated at the Benedictine Abbey by an anchoress when she was about eight years of age. At the age of fourteen she became a consecrated nun attached to the Abbey, where she lived a quiet life of prayer for many years. At the age of 38, after the anchoress' death, she was chosen as the new leader of a growing group of nuns. Hildegard led a remarkable and unusual life for a woman of her day. She was an avid composer of sacred music and liturgy, in addition to poems and plays. She also wrote heavily on theology, natural medicine, and natural science. At the age of 42, at the command of God, Hildegard began writing down what she saw in her visions. Her works were widely read, even by the Pope, and leaders around the world sought her council. Her fame as a mystic and prophetess grew, earning her the name "Sibyl of the Rhine." More nuns flocked to join her, causing Hildegard to establish a new monastery at Rupertsberg. She wrote proficiently on the harmony of created nature and man's need to live in balance with it, especially in virtue, morality, and the love of God, which led Pope Benedict XVI to declare her the fourth female Doctor of the Church in 2012 alongside Teresa of Avila, Catherine of Siena, and Thérèse of Lisieux.  Because her works were far ahead of her time she is regarded as a historical phenomenon. Hildegard of Bingen is considered the founder of scientific natural history in Germany. Her feast day is September 17th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 18, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-18/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">3b8515250eb5cd7581237f6031a7d7aea2a4ef6f</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"In the first place it should be known that if a person is seeking God, his beloved is seeking him much more." <strong>St. John of the Cross</strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Marriage releases the flesh from its individual selfishness for the service of the family; the vow of chastity releases the flesh not only from the narrow and circumscribed family, where there can still be selfishness, but also for the service of that family that embraces all humanity. That is why the Church asks those who consecrate themselves to the redemption of the world to take a vow and to surrender all selfishness, that they may belong to no one family and yet belong to all. That is why in that larger family of the kingdom of God, the priest is called “Father” —because he has begotten children not in the flesh, but in the spirit.”<br/>
—Venerable Fulton Sheen, p. 117</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"Hark, your watchmen lift up their voice, together they sing for joy; for eye to eye they see the return of the Lord to Zion. Break forth together into singing, you waste places of Jerusalem; for the Lord has comforted his people, he has redeemed Jerusalem. The Lord has bared his holy arm before the eyes of all the nations; and all the ends of the earth shall see the salvation of our God." <strong>Isaiah 52:8-10</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Joseph of Cupertino" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4336.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Joseph of Cupertino</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Joseph of Cupertino (1603-1663) was the son of a poor Italian carpenter. His father died before he was born, leaving his mother destitute. As a result Joseph was underfed and often sick. He was an intellectually dull child who constantly found himself the worse off in every situation. He was awkward, absent-minded, unintelligent, and difficult to be around. Many people thought he was good for nothing–including his own mother, who treated him harshly and considered him a burden. Added to the scorn he received from everyone, at the age of eight he began receiving ecstatic visions for which he was also ridiculed. At the age of seventeen Joseph found work with the Capuchin Franciscan friars, eventually joining their order once they recognized his holiness beneath his irritating demeanor. His ecstasies became more pronounced, and he would often levitate or float as they happened. These ecstasies could be triggered easily through the mention of anything heavenly, or by any mortification. These occurrences became a spectacle and disturbance to others and caused Joseph much suffering; they were a cross he would bear his whole life. For example, as a priest he could not celebrate Mass publicly due to his distracting ecstasies. He was even reported to the Inquisition for fear he was involved in witchcraft. Yet St. Joseph lived a life of deep prayer and severe penance through continual fasting, subjecting himself every year to seven Lents of forty days each. Sometimes called “The Flying Saint,” St. Joseph of Cupertino is also the patron of air crews and aviators. His feast day is September 18th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 19, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-19/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">b1ad9ca35a31c50201b9940a39d45ff8c8ae78b0</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"The closer one approaches to God, the simpler one becomes." <strong>St. Teresa of Avila</strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Meekness is spiritual; meekness is joy. And we should all strive to have in our hearts that joy that is contagiously cheerful. We need not think that we must be continually joking; nor should we believe that even-temperedness must express its happiness in laughter. We may and undoubtedly will have bothersome worries, but we can and should be even-tempered, retain our peace of heart, be meek in spite of them. We can at least bear with life’s small problems in such a way as not to allow them to rush upon others. Even temper is attractive, helps the community spirit, keeps down all that ends to anger for it seeks under varying circumstances to be pleasant, amiable, agreeable, mild, patient. It is, in fact, the practice of many virtues.”<br/>
—Matt Fradd, p.79</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"Thus says the Lord who made the earth, the Lord who formed it to establish it—the Lord is his name: Call to me and I will answer you, and will tell you great and hidden things which you have not known." <strong>Jeremiah 33: 2-3</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Januarius" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3720.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Januarius</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Januarius (d. 305 A.D.), also known as San Gennaro, was the Bishop of Benevento, Italy. Little is known of his early life. He was arrested and imprisoned for his faith while visiting other Christians in jail during the persecution of Roman Emperor Diocletian. Many attempts were made to kill him, but one after another they failed. He was thrown into a fiery furnace, but he came out unscathed. He was then thrown to wild beasts in the amphitheater, but they did not attack. He was finally beheaded, and his blood was collected by Christians and kept in a sealed glass vial for veneration. The vial of blood is still kept today in the Naples cathedral, and it has continually demonstrated miraculous properties for which no scientific explanation has been offered. St. Januarius' blood liquefies and becomes fresh on particular occasions throughout the year, especially his feast day, for which the saint has become famous. This phenomenon has been occurring with regularity for centuries, and is one of the "blood miracles" that is historically well-documented among the relics of certain saints. He is the patron saint of blood banks and the city of Naples, Italy. St. Januarius's feast day is September 19th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 20, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-20/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">50e29b67285d857e4cffd1c2e44bd4d4c0c042dc</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"We have received baptism, entrance into the Church, and the honor of being called Christians. Yet what good will this do us if we are Christians in name only and not in fact?" <strong>St. Andrew Kim Taegon </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“The second stage of contemplation and the sixth of prayer is that of quiet. This is the union of the will with God, who, as highest Good, attracts it forcefully so that in Him alone it may find its rest. Infinite power, goodness, gentleness, and sweetness, with God’s gifts of fear, piety, fortitude, and wisdom, overwhelm it and at the same time take it captive, set it ablaze, fill it with caresses, and drawing it near…there the soul finds for a time every now and then—times that seem to it short however long they last—its full rest, its refreshment and strength, its peace and happiness.”<br/>
—J.G Arintero, O.P., p.44-45</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"Blessed are you when they insult you and persecute you and utter every kind of evil against you [falsely] because of me. Rejoice and be glad, for your reward will be great in heaven. Thus they persecuted the prophets who were before you." <strong>Matthew 5:11-12</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Andrew Kim Tae-gon" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4342.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Andrew Kim Tae-gon</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p> St. Andrew Kim Tae-gon (1821-1846) was born to a noble family in Korea, and was baptized at the age of 15 after his parents converted to the Catholic faith. Andrew's father, great-grandfather, and great-uncle were martyred during the government's staunch persecution against Christianity, leaving the remaining family in poverty. Andrew was later chosen to travel over 1,000 miles to the nearest seminary in China to be trained for the priesthood. He was ordained in Shanghai as the first native Korean priest in the Church's history of evangelizing in that country. He returned to Korea in secrecy to avoid detection by the authorities. Once back in his hometown, he worked to catechize the faithful until his bishop summoned him to Seoul to help smuggle French missionaries from China into Korea, with the aid of Chinese fishermen. During this operation he was caught and imprisoned by the border patrol, and charged as a traitor to his country. He was tortured and beheaded on September 16, 1846, at the age of 25. Pope John Paul II canonized Fr. Andrew Kim Tae-gon, along with 102 other Korean martyrs, on May 6, 1984. St. Andrew Kim Tae-gon is the patron saint of Korea. His feast day is celebrated on September 20th.  	 </p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 21, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-21/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">c8688de8ef68ba7675eaa90b55b3c3ed5309bbe8</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"For me, prayer is a surge of the heart; it is a simple look turned toward heaven, it is a cry of recognition and of love, embracing both trial and joy." <strong>St. Therese of Lisieux</strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“There is no such thing as a dull, futile, or useless experience. Every sorrow loses its sting, because everything is an opportunity to glorify God. Saint Paul wrote, “For the sake of Christ, then, I am content with weaknesses, insults, hardships, persecutions, and calamities: for when I am weak, then I am strong” (2 Cor 12:10). Once you have learned to find contentment in adversity, all of life becomes changed with light and hope and joy.”<br/>
–J. Augustine Wetta, O.S.B, p. 103</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"As Jesus passed on from there, He saw a man called Matthew sitting at the tax office; and He said to him, “Follow me.” And he rose and followed Him." <strong>Matthew 9:9</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Matthew" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4343.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Matthew</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p> St. Matthew the Apostle (1st c.) was a Jew who also went by the name of Levi. He was from Galilee and served in Capernaum as a tax collector for Herod Antipas before becoming a disciple of Jesus. It was in the home of St. Matthew that Jesus dined with the "sinners and tax collectors."  Under Jesus' influence St. Matthew was led to repentance for the evil he had done as a tax-collector, a position despised by his fellow Jews. He repaid those he cheated four-fold, sold all his possessions, and followed Christ as one of the twelve Apostles. St. Matthew preached among the Jews for fifteen years following the Resurrection and Ascension of Jesus. He is the author of the Gospel that bears his name, which he wrote to convince the Jews that Jesus Christ was the Messiah promised to Israel. According to tradition, St. Matthew the Apostle brought the Gospel to Syria, Media, Persia, Parthia, and finished his preaching in Ethiopia with a martyr’s death. He is the patron of guards, bankers, accountants, security forces, and stock brokers. His feast day is September 21st.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
