<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
  <title>Morning Offering (Unofficial RSS)</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/</link>
  <description>Unofficial, personal-use RSS feed created from morningoffering.com daily page.</description>
  <language>en-us</language>
  <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 06:08:09 -0400</lastBuildDate>
  <item>
  <title>Morning Offering for October 1, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/10-01/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">1d7b26ec7e9d40ce515a811e8e4cfb32f571c77d</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"A word or a smile is often enough to put fresh life in a despondent soul." <strong>St. Therese of Lisieux </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Prayer, for me, is simply a raising of the heart, a simple glance towards Heaven, an expression of love and gratitude in the midst of trial, as well as in times of joy; in a word, it is something noble and supernatural expanding my soul and uniting it to God. Whenever my soul is so dry that I am incapable of a single good thought, I always say an Our Father or a Hail Mary very slowly, and these prayers alone cheer me up and nourish my soul with divine food.”<br/>
—St. Therese of Lisieux, p. 141</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"I urge you therefore, brothers, by the mercies of God, to offer your bodies as a living sacrifice, holy and pleasing to God, your spiritual worship. Do not conform yourselves to this age but be transformed by the renewal of your mind, that you may discern what is the will of God, what is good and pleasing and perfect." <strong>Romans 12:1-2</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Therese of Lisieux" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3723.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Therese of Lisieux</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p> St. Therese of Lisieux (1873-1897) was the last of nine children born to Saints Louis and Zelie Martin in Alencon, France. Her family was devoutly religious, and all five surviving siblings, all daughters, entered the convent. From an early age Therese desired to give herself totally to Jesus. Her happy childhood gave way to trial following the death of her mother when she was four years old. This event changed her personality from merry and bright to withdrawn and sensitive. She also suffered a strange illness that brought her near death. Her sisters prayed for her recovery, and Therese was completely healed after she saw the Virgin Mary statue in her room smile down on her. Just before her 14th birthday, on Christmas Eve, Therese had a mystical experience of the Child Jesus. Her sensitiveness disappeared and her faith was greatly fortified. She attended daily Mass with her father and cultivated her strong desire for the salvation of souls. At the age of 15 she obtained special permission to enter the Carmelite convent in Lisieux where two of her sisters were professed. Recognizing her youth and weakness, and unable to do the great things for God in the world that her heart desired, she determined that she would follow the path of spiritual childhood at the feet of Jesus, as his "Little Flower", and instead focus on small acts of kindness for love of Jesus and interior acts of self-denial, a spirituality called "The Little Way."  Therese died of Tuberculosis at the age of 24, and her high degree of holiness was discovered through her autobiography, Story of a Soul. Her "Little Way" became profoundly influential around the world, and although she was not a learned scholar, her deep theological life caused Pope St. John Paul II to declare her a Doctor of the Church. She is the patron against sickness, tuberculosis, and loss of parents, as well as of pilots, air crews, florists, missionaries, and the sick. St. Therese of Lisieux's feast day is October 1st.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> the Holy Rosary</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Catholic Church designates October as the Month of the Holy Rosary. During this month the faithful venerate the Blessed Virgin Mary especially under her title of Our Lady of the Rosary, and make special effort to honor the Holy Rosary with group recitations and rosary processions. St. Dominic de Guzman, the founder of the Order of Preachers, is the saint to whom Our Lady famously appeared and gave the prayers of the Holy Rosary to assist him as a spiritual weapon in combating heresy and leading souls back to the one, true Catholic faith.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the the Holy Rosary" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4965.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 30, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-30/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">926fb452bdf7dcf82c4c2d31a39e58b10c392ecf</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"God loves those who thank Him even in suffering." <strong>St. Arnold Janssen </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Chastity is the most unpopular of the Christian virtues. There is no getting away from it; the Christian rule is, ‘Either marriage, with complete faithfulness to your partner, or else total abstinence.’ Now this is so difficult and so contrary to our instincts, that obviously either Christianity is wrong or our sexual instinct, as it now is, has gone wrong. One or the other. Of course, being a Christian, I think it is the instinct which has gone wrong … God knows our situation; He will not judge us as if we had no difficulties to overcome. What matters is the sincerity and perseverance of our will to overcome them. Before we can be cured we must want to be cured. Those who really wish for help will get it; but for many modern people even the wish is difficult … We may, indeed, be sure that perfect chastity—like perfect charity—will not be attained by any merely human efforts. You must ask for God’s help. Even when you have done so, it may seem to you for a long time that no help, or less help than you need, is being given. Never mind. After each failure, ask forgiveness, pick yourself up and try again. Very often what God first helps us towards is not the virtue itself but just this power of always trying again. For however important chastity (or courage, or truthfulness, or any other virtue) may be, this process trains us in habits of the soul which are more important still. It cures our illusions about ourselves and teaches us to depend on God. We learn, on the one hand, that we cannot trust ourselves even in our best moments, and, on the other, that we need not despair even in our worst, for our failures are forgiven. The only fatal thing is to sit down content with anything less than perfection.”<br/>
—C. S. Lewis, p. 95</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"It is he who made the earth by his power, who established the world by his wisdom, and by his understanding stretched out the heavens." <strong>Jeremiah 10:12</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Jerome" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3684.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Jerome</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p> St. Jerome (347 – 420) was born to a wealthy pagan family in Dalmatia. He was sent to Rome for his schooling and there converted to Christianity, being baptized by Pope Liberius. He studied theology and traveled widely to the important intellectual and theological centers across the newly-established Christian Empire. He was ordained a priest at Antioch and lived many years as a hermit in a nearby desert. He became an extraordinary scholar, considered to be the most learned of the Latin Church Fathers.  Because of his many significant theological works, most notably the thirty years he spent writing the Latin translation of the Bible (the Latin Vulgate), he is one of the most influential and orthodox theologians in the life of the early Church. In his final years Saint Jerome lived in a monastery that he founded in the Holy Land near Bethlehem, where he worked on writing histories and biographies in addition to drawing deeper into a life of prayer and asceticism. For his important scholarly contributions St. Jerome was named a Doctor of the Church. He is the patron of libraries, archaeologists, students, and translators. St. Jerome's feast day is September 30th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 29, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-29/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">879b5ffd7d8567054324e394a8aa72a983348162</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"When you awake in the night, transport yourself quickly in spirit before the Tabernacle, saying: 'Behold, my God, I come to adore You, to praise, thank, and love you, and to keep you company with all the Angels.'" <strong>St. John Vianney </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“With regard to the nobility of the angels, we need only consider that they possess a privileged place amongst all the creations of God. For they are of a purely spiritual substance and of an immortal nature, immune from the sufferings, disease, aging, and death to which corporeal beings are all subject. Their intelligence is such that they are free from all errors and ignorance with respect to knowledge of created things. In addition to this perfectly illuminated light of intelligence, the angels possess a will which is completely and utterly constant, such that it may not be overcome or made to waver by any perturbation or adversity.”<br/>
–St. Aloysius Gonzaga, p.32</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"For he will give his angels charge of you to guard you in all your ways. On their hands they will bear you up, lest you dash your foot against a stone." <strong>Psalm 91:11-12</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="Archangels" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3683.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">Archangels</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>The Archangels St. Gabriel, St. Michael, and St. Raphael share a feast day on September 29th. These are the only three angels mentioned by name in Sacred Scripture.  St. Gabriel means “Power of God." He is the messenger or herald angel most famous for appearing to the Blessed Virgin Mary at the Annunciation (Luke 1:11-38).  St. Michael means “Who is like God?" He is the warrior angel, the famous foe of Satan, who is the champion of God’s people and guardian and protector of the Church (Rev. 12:7-9).  St. Raphael means “God has healed." He is a companion and healing angel, most famous for curing a man's blindness and for traveling with Tobiah in the book of Tobit (Tob. 12).</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 28, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-28/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">0032b0a00861b481fff6fc1d615b314bbcc078ec</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"Let us make up for lost time. Let us give to God the time that remains to us." <strong>St. Alphonsus Liguori </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Suppress Interior Noise – God created your soul silent and keeps it inviolate at baptism. He filled it with Himself, nothing other than Himself. It is later, little by little that the world bursts in. Noise invades, covering the soft voice of God. Since then, the racket amplifies itself. Return to your baptismal silence, my brother! Noise has three generators: memories, curiosity, and worries. Paralyze their action.”<br/>
— An Anonymous Carthusian Monk</p><p> </p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"I, then, a prisoner for the Lord, urge you to live in a manner worthy of the call you have received, with all humility and gentleness, with patience, bearing with one another through love, striving to preserve the unity of the spirit through the bond of peace." <strong>Ephesians 4:1-3</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Wenceslaus" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3722.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Wenceslaus</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Wenceslaus (907–935 A.D.) was the son of the Duke of Bohemia. His grandfather was converted to Christianity by the missionaries Sts. Cyril and Methodius. His mother, Dragomir, was the daughter of a pagan tribal chief who was baptized at her marriage. After the death of his father, Wenceslaus received a Christian upbringing from his grandmother, St. Ludmila, while his mother reverted to her pagan ways. Dragomir reigned as regent, had St. Ludmila killed, and worked to oppose the spread of Christianity in Bohemia. When St. Wenceslaus was 18 he took control of the government and exiled his mother. St. Wenceslaus was described as a pious, humble, and intelligent ruler who worked to established Christianity in the land that would become part of the Holy Roman Empire. He was known for his vow of virginity, his many virtues, and his life of prayer and good works. After a political dispute arose, his mother and his younger brother, called Boleslaus the Cruel, plotted his murder along with a group of disaffected nobles. Boleslaus invited his brother to celebrate the feast of Sts. Cosmas and Damian, and arranged to have him assassinated on his way to Mass. St. Wenceslaus muttered words of forgiveness as he died, and his body was buried at the murder site. His brother succeeded him as Duke of Bohemia. Three years later Boleslaus repented of his crime, and had his brother's remains transferred to the Church of St. Vitus in Prague. Wenceslaus was considered a saint by the people at the time of his death. His feast day is September 28th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 27, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-27/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">afd77e0a87323243d6cba63395b3478ded686c03</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"We should strive to keep our hearts open to the sufferings and wretchedness of other people, and pray continually that God may grant us that spirit of compassion which is truly the spirit of God." <strong>St. Vincent de Paul </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Let us beware of complaints, resentments, and evil-speaking against those who are ill-disposed to us, discontented with us, or hostile to our plans and arrangements, or who even persecute us with injuries, insults, and calumnies. Rather let us go on treating them as cordially as at first, or more so, as far as possible showing them esteem, always speaking well of them, doing them good, serving them on occasion, even to the point of taking shame and disgrace upon ourselves, if necessary to save their honor. All this ought to be done, first, to overcome evil with good, according to the teaching of the Apostles; and secondly, because they are our allies rather than our adversaries, as they aid us to destroy self-love, which is our greatest foe; and since it is they who give us an opportunity to gain merit, they ought to be considered our dearest friends.”<br/>
—St. Vincent de Paul, p.413</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"Whoever loves me will keep my word, and my Father will love him, and we will come to him and make our dwelling with him. Whoever does not love me does not keep my words; yet the word you hear is not mine but that of the Father who sent me." <strong>John 14:23-24</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Vincent de Paul" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4358.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Vincent de Paul</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Vincent de Paul (1581–1660) was born in France to a peasant farming family. As a child he grew up herding sheep, and showed such an aptitude for his studies that his father sold the family oxen to fund his seminary education. After his ordination in 1600, St. Vincent worked in Toulouse as a tutor to pay for his doctorate. In 1605, while traveling by sea, he was captured by Turkish pirates. He was taken to Tunis in Africa and sold into slavery four times before escaping in 1607 along with his master, whom he had coverted to the faith. St. Vincent then continued his studies in Rome, and afterwards returned to France. He served as a parish priest and ministered to the nobility; however, two life-changing encounters with destitute people inspired him to begin work among the poor and marginalized. He gathered the wealthy women of his parish to collect funds for missionary projects. From this group came the Daughters of Charity of St. Vincent de Paul. He also founded an Order of priests, the Vincentians, who, during a time of general laxity and ignorance among the clergy, devoted themselves to the Evangelical Councils while serving in small towns and villages. He committed himself to the education of priests and conducted many retreats for their spiritual formation. He also ministered to convicts suffering deplorable conditions in prison, and won many to the faith in addition to building them a hospital. St. Vincent renewed the faith of France during a time of spiritual crisis. For this he was named the patron of charitable works. He is also the patron of the St. Vincent de Paul Society, an organization dedicated to the service of the poor, now working in 132 countries. His feast day is September 27th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 26, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-26/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">d0003f385e852e7439b5df71caa123754fe7cc29</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"Holiness consists simply in doing God's will, and being just what God wants us to be." <strong>St. Therese of Lisieux - The Little Flower </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Through the sacraments of Christian initiation, man receives the new life of Christ. Now we carry this life ‘in earthen vessels’, and it remains ‘hidden with Christ in God’. We are still in our ‘earthly tent’, subject to suffering, illness, and death. This new life as a child of God can be weakened and even lost by sin. The Lord Jesus Christ, physician of our souls and bodies, who forgave the sins of the paralytic and restored him to bodily health, has willed that his Church continue, in the power of the Holy Spirit, his work of healing and salvation, even among her own members. This is the purpose of the two sacraments of healing: the sacrament of Penance and the sacrament of Anointing of the Sick.”<br/>
—The Catechism of the Catholic Church, 1420-21</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"Commit your way to the Lord; trust in him, and he will act. He will bring forth your vindication as the light, and your right as the noonday. Be still before the Lord, and wait patiently for him; fret not yourself over him who prospers in his way, over the man who carries out evil devices!" <strong>Psalm 37:5-7</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="Sts. Cosmas &amp; Damian" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4357.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">Sts. Cosmas &amp; Damian</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>Sts. Cosmas and Damian (d. 287 A.D.) were twin brothers born in Arabia. They both became skilled physicians who practiced in Asia Minor. They took no money for their medical services, for which they were well-respected. Because of their charity they drew many to the Catholic faith. During the Christian persecution under the Roman Emperor Diocletian, Cosmas and Damian were targeted, arrested, and tortured. After being miraculously preserved from injury throughout their cruel tortures, holding firm in their faith to the end, they were finally killed by beheading. They were martyred together with their three brothers. Their remains were buried in Syria and many miracles were attributed to them. In gratitude for the healing he received through the intercession of Sts. Cosmas and Damian, Roman Emperor Justinian I (6th c.) restored a church dedicated to their honor in Constantinople, which became a place of pilgrimage. Sts. Cosmas and Damian are regarded as the patron saints of physicians, surgeons, and pharmacists. They are mentioned by name in the Roman Canon of the Mass, and share a feast day on September 26th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 25, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-25/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">cbf5a9a446d737ef62f051f954145a8a1cf88d5a</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"Consider God's charity. Where else have we ever seen someone who has been offended voluntarily paying out his life for those who have offended him?" <strong>St. Catherine of Siena </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“I remind you, My daughter, that as often as you hear the clock strike the third hour, immerse yourself completely in My mercy, adoring and glorifying it; invoke its omnipotence for the whole world, and particularly for poor sinners; for at that moment mercy was opened wide for every soul. In this hour you can obtain everything for yourself and for others for the asking; it was the hour of grace for the whole world—mercy triumphed over justice. My daughter, try your best to make the Stations of the Cross in this hour, provided that your duties permit it; and if you are not able to make the Stations of the Cross, then at least step into the chapel for a moment and adore, in the Blessed Sacrament, My Heart, which is full of mercy; and should you be unable to step into the chapel, immerse yourself in prayer there where you happen to be, if only for a very brief instant.”<br/>
—Jesus to St. Faustina Kowalska, (1572)</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"So, as you received Christ Jesus the Lord, walk in him, rooted in him and built upon him and established in the faith as you were taught, abounding in thanksgiving." <strong>Colossians 2:6-7</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Cleophas" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3721.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Cleophas</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Cleophas (1st c.) was one of Jesus' seventy disciples, and one of the two disciples who were traveling along the road to Emmaus after the crucifixion and resurrection of Jesus in Jerusalem, as recounted in Luke's Gospel. The resurrected Jesus appeared and walked along the road with St. Cleophas and his companion, explaining the events of his Passion and how they fulfilled the Holy Scriptures. According to one tradition, Cleophas (also known as Alphaeus), was a relative of Jesus; he was the brother of St. Joseph, and therefore was Jesus' uncle. Cleophas was the husband of St. Mary of Cleophas, and they had three sons we know by name: St. Simon, St. James the Less, and St. Jude. St. Cleophas, through his daughter Mary Salome, was also grandfather to St. James the Greater and St. John. Therefore three of his sons and two of his grandsons were among the Twelve Apostles. According to tradition, St. Cleophas was martyred by the Jewish authorities in the same home in which he received Jesus as a guest. His feast day is September 25th.</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 24, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-24/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">07e75711ac536c49697ca83a17a050d7fc30ec86</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"The Divine Heart is an ocean full of all good things, wherein poor souls can cast all their needs; it is an ocean full of joy to drown all our sadness, an ocean of humility to drown our folly, an ocean of mercy to those in distress, an ocean of love in which to submerge our poverty." <strong>St. Margaret Mary </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“I never found anyone so religious and devout as not to have sometimes a subtraction of grace, or feel a diminution of fervor. No saint was ever so highly rapt and illuminated as not to be tempted sooner or later. For he is not worthy of the high contemplation of God who has not, for God’s sake, been exercised with some tribulation. For temptation going before is usually a sign of ensuing consolation. For heavenly comfort is promised to such as have been proved by temptation. To him that overcometh, saith our Lord, I will give to eat of the tree of life.”<br/>
—Thomas à Kempis, p. 65</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"But you, be self-possessed in all circumstances; put up with hardship; perform the work of an evangelist; fulfill your ministry. For I am already being poured out like a libation, and the time of my departure is at hand. I have competed well; I have finished the race; I have kept the faith. From now on the crown of righteousness awaits me, which the Lord, the just judge, will award to me on that day, and not only to me, but to all who have longed for his appearance." <strong>2 Timothy 4:5-8</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Gerard Sagredo" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4349.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Gerard Sagredo</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Gerard Sagredo (980–1046 A.D.) was born in Venice, Italy. From an early age he desired to dedicate his life to God, and as a young man became a Benedictine monk. He first served as abbot at a monastery in Venice, but left to make a pilgrimage to the Holy Land. While passing through Hungary he met the Hungarian king, St. Stephen, who asked him to stay in his country to evangelize and minister to his people. St. Gerard agreed, and was named Bishop of Csanád and the royal tutor of the Hungarian prince. He ministered tirelessly among the Hungarian people and helped to convert the whole country to Christianity, for which he is called the "Apostle of Hungary." After the death of King St. Stephen there was a pagan uprising against the Christians, and St. Gerard was martyred for the faith along with two others. His death took place on a hill in Budapest which is now named after him; according to one tradition he was placed in a barrel lined with spikes, and rolled down the hill. He was declared a saint in 1083 by Pope St. Gregory VII. St. Gerard Sagredo is the patron saint of Hungary, and his feast day is September 24th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 23, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-23/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">8aecaedbe40694378000e1a4825ba082657c60ee</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"You must speak to Jesus, not only with your lips, but also with your heart; actually, on certain occasions, you should speak with only your heart." <strong>Saint Padre Pio</strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Always be impartial and just in your deeds. Put yourself into your neighbor’s place, and him in yours, and then you will judge fairly . . . Frequently, therefore, examine your heart, whether it is so disposed towards your neighbor, as you would have his disposed towards you, were you to change places; for this is the true test.”<br/>
—St. Francis de Sales, p. 226</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"O give thanks to the Lord, for he is good; for his steadfast love endures forever." <strong>1 Chronicles 16:34</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Padre Pio of Pietrelcina" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4247.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Padre Pio of Pietrelcina</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Padre Pio of Pietrelcina (1887–1968) was born to peasant farmers in southern Italy. By the time he was 5 years old he practiced a life of penance and made the decision to give himself completely to God. He grew up working in the fields, and at the age of 19 joined the Capuchin Franciscan friars. His Franciscan spirituality was characterized by a life of poverty, love of nature, and charity to those in need, especially to those who were his "spiritual children." St. Padre Pio had many spiritual gifts and was a great miracle-worker. These were well-documented from multiple reliable sources and included bilocation, levitation, reading souls, and physical healing by touch. Word of his holiness spread and people both pious and curious flocked to see him, especially to have him hear their confession. He is the first priest known to have received the stigmata, for which he suffered suspicion and investigation. Because of the unusual supernatural phenomena surrounding his life, he is considered one of the great visionaries and mystics of the Church. Padre Pio died in 1968 at the age of 81. He was canonized by Pope St. John Paul II in 2002. Because of the many miracles he performed during his life, he is commonly invoked as a healing saint for various ailments. His feast day is September 23rd.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 22, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-22/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">95ed0a3b1392a68f37b67ada3d2953ad3a00fae5</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"Grant me, O Lord my God, a mind to know you, a heart to seek you, wisdom to find you, conduct pleasing to you, faithful perseverance in waiting for you, and a hope of finally embracing you." <strong>St. Thomas Aquinas </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“There is not a moment in which God does not present Himself under the cover of some pain to be endured, of some consolation to be enjoyed, or of some duty to be performed. All that takes place within us, around us, or through us, contains and conceals His divine action. It is really and truly there present, but invisibly present, so that we are always surprised and do not recognise His operation until it has ceased. If we could lift the veil, and if we were attentive and watchful God would continually reveal Himself to us, and we should see His divine action in everything that happened to us, and rejoice in it. At each successive occurrence we should exclaim: ‘It is the Lord’, and we should accept every fresh circumstance as a gift of God. We should look upon creatures as feeble tools in the hands of an able workman, and should discover easily that nothing was wanting to us, and that the constant providence of God disposed Him to bestow upon us at every moment whatever we required.”<br/>
—Fr. Jean-Pierre de Caussade, p. 49</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"The way of the righteous is level; thou dost make smooth the path of the righteous. In the path of thy judgments, O Lord, we wait for thee; thy memorial name is the desire of our soul. My soul yearns for thee in the night, my spirit within me earnestly seeks thee. For when thy judgments are in the earth, the inhabitants of the world learn righteousness." <strong>Isaiah 26:7-9</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="Saint Ignatius of Santhia" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4327.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">Saint Ignatius of Santhia</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Ignatius of Santhia (1686-1770) was born in Italy to an upper-class family. He received his early education from a devout priest, a relative of his mother, who inspired him to join the priesthood. He studied philosophy and theology, and after his ordination served as a diocesan priest for six years. St. Ignatius earned a reputation as an excellent preacher of retreats and missions, and he had a promising future within the diocese. His family and parishioners were surprised and disappointed when he decided to join the Capuchin Franciscans in Turin as a poor, humble friar. However, St. Ignatius flourished in the poverty and simplicity of the Franciscan way of life. He became well-known for his wisdom and sanctity, and many people from all walks of life came to him for confession and spiritual direction. He had a great devotion to the Blessed Virgin Mary and prayed the rosary faithfully. He served God with humble obedience and inspired this virtue in the Franciscan novices over whom he had charge. He spent his last years on a sickbed where he continued to hear confessions and give direction to his visitors. St. Ignatius of Santhia's feast day is September 22nd.</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 15, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-15/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">5cdb3e86ca2a8552804e1b0a3c7b1ecb0e214c81</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"I see clearly with the interior eye, that the sweet God loves with a pure love the creature that He has created, and has a hatred for nothing but sin, which is more opposed to Him than can be thought or imagined." <strong>St. Catherine of Genoa </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“If we have any distinct concept of blessedness connected with mourning, it could likely have been that it is a blessed thing to be rid of it. Are not mourners by widely accepted definition the unhappy ones? Obviously, if a mourner is blessed, then it has to mean that he is blessed to have gotten out of this painful predicament, to have escaped from this sorrowful situation, to have fended off suffering. And so we might well have written the third Beatitude like this: Blessed are they who enjoy the comfort of not having anything to mourn about. But then we run up against the hard fact that this is just not what Christ said…We shall have to deal with the words that our blessed Savior uttered and not with the words that we think He ought to have uttered.”<br/>
—Mother Francis, PCC, p.36</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"Make me understand the way of thy precepts, and I will meditate on thy wondrous works. My soul melts away for sorrow; strengthen me according to thy word! Put false ways far from me; and graciously teach me thy law! I have chosen the way of faithfulness, I set thy ordinances before me. I cleave to thy testimonies, O Lord; let me not be put to shame! I will run in the way of thy commandments when thou enlargest my understanding!" <strong>Psalm 119:27-32</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Catherine of Genoa" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3879.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Catherine of Genoa</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Catherine (1447–1510) was born into an aristocratic family in Genoa, Italy. She was a quiet, obedient, physically beautiful, and holy child who devoted herself to prayer and penance. At the age of 13 she made an attempt to enter a convent, but was rejected. At the age of 16 she consented to a marriage arranged by her family for political and financial gain. Her husband was faithless and violent, and their marriage was miserable. Catherine did not bear any children, and for the first five years lived as a hermit in her fine home. After this time, upon her family's rebuke of her solitude, she began to engage in the kind of social activity expected for her state in life. This only increased her weariness and depression, and led to the loss of her religious fervor. Catherine prayed earnestly for assistance in her trouble. Taking the advice of her sister, who was a nun, Catherine went to confession, and through the sacrament had a profound mystical experience in which she clearly saw the depth of her sinfulness contrasted with the depth of God's love. From that point on she renewed her commitment to rigorous prayer, penance, and works of mercy, and God continued to favor her with mystical visions. Catherine later won the conversion of her husband, and they were received into the Third Order of St. Francis. Together they cared for the poor and sick in the Genoa hospital, over which Catherine became administrator. St. Catherine's mystical visions were recorded by her confessor toward the end of her life, the most famous being her Treatise of Purgatory. Her feast day is celebrated on September 15th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 16, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-16/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">9370124272401db330dd297fcd0177549f21aad8</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"Prayer is the best armor we have, it is the key which opens the heart of God." <strong>Saint Padre Pio of Pietrelcina </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“In the case of biblical parables we must always expect that the addressees will be brought into a situation in which they believe they are going to enjoy a thrilling story—and then all at once everything changes: they are confronted with the will of God or the evil situation in which they are living in God’s eyes.”<br/>
—Gerhard Lohfink, p.17</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"If you love me, you will keep my commandments. And I will ask the Father, and he will give you another Advocate to be with you always, the Spirit of truth, which the world cannot accept, because it neither sees nor knows it. But you know it, because it remains with you, and will be in you." <strong>John 14:15-17</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="Pope St. Cornelius" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3504.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">Pope St. Cornelius</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>Pope St. Cornelius (d. 253 A.D.) was a Roman citizen and a holy priest who became the twenty-first successor to the chair of St. Peter, following a fourteen-month vacancy when Pope St. Fabian was martyred by Roman Emperor Decius. When the Emperor temporarily left Rome, the persecution against the Christians subsided long enough for the Church to elect St. Cornelius as the new Roman Pontiff. During Pope St. Cornelius' two year reign a great controversy arose as to what to do with Catholics who apostatized from the Christian faith under threat of death during the persecution. Many were being received back to the sacraments without any penance. In response to the scandal, some maintained that apostates could not be forgiven and could only be admitted back to the sacraments if they were re-baptized. Chief among them was a priest named Novatian, who, as a result of the scandal, caused a schism when he had himself consecrated as an anti-pope. In response, Pope St. Cornelius convened a synod of bishops to confirm his rightful authority as Pope. Novatian was excommunicated and his doctrine was condemned as heresy. Pope St. Cornelius proclaimed that the Church had the power and authority to forgive repentant apostasy, and that converted apostates could be readmitted to the sacraments after true contrition with adequate penance. Soon a new wave of persecution against the Christians broke out, and Pope St. Cornelius was driven into exile and martyred. His feast day is celebrated on September 16th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 17, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-17/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">ef4bf2f1ce76dc1af7106064ba05a562f31428ef</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"May the Holy Spirit enkindle you with the fire of His Love so that you may persevere, unfailingly, in the love of His service. Thus you may merit to become, at last, a living stone in the celestial Jerusalem." <strong>St. Hildegard von Bingen </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“You have never begrudged the martyrs their triumph but rather trained them for it. And so I am asking you to be consistent with the lessons you teach them. Just beg for me the courage and endurance not only to speak but also to will what is right, so that I may not only be called a Christian, but prove to be one. For if I prove myself to be a Christian by martyrdom, then people will call me one, and my loyalty to Christ will be apparent when the world sees me no more. Nothing you can see is truly good. For our Lord Jesus Christ, now that he has returned to his Father, has revealed himself more clearly. Our task is not one of producing persuasive propaganda; Christianity shows its greatness when it is hated by the world.”<br/>
—St. Ignatius of Antioch, p. 194</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"The Lord bless you and keep you; the Lord make his face to shine upon you, and be gracious to you; the Lord lift up his countenance upon you, and give you peace." <strong>Numbers 6:24-26</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Hildegard von Bingen" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3502.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Hildegard von Bingen</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p> St. Hildegard von Bingen (1098–1179) was born to a large and noble German family. She began to have mystical visions at the age of three which continued throughout her life. Her parents, promising her to the service of God, sent her to be educated at the Benedictine Abbey by an anchoress when she was about eight years of age. At the age of fourteen she became a consecrated nun attached to the Abbey, where she lived a quiet life of prayer for many years. At the age of 38, after the anchoress' death, she was chosen as the new leader of a growing group of nuns. Hildegard led a remarkable and unusual life for a woman of her day. She was an avid composer of sacred music and liturgy, in addition to poems and plays. She also wrote heavily on theology, natural medicine, and natural science. At the age of 42, at the command of God, Hildegard began writing down what she saw in her visions. Her works were widely read, even by the Pope, and leaders around the world sought her council. Her fame as a mystic and prophetess grew, earning her the name "Sibyl of the Rhine." More nuns flocked to join her, causing Hildegard to establish a new monastery at Rupertsberg. She wrote proficiently on the harmony of created nature and man's need to live in balance with it, especially in virtue, morality, and the love of God, which led Pope Benedict XVI to declare her the fourth female Doctor of the Church in 2012 alongside Teresa of Avila, Catherine of Siena, and Thérèse of Lisieux.  Because her works were far ahead of her time she is regarded as a historical phenomenon. Hildegard of Bingen is considered the founder of scientific natural history in Germany. Her feast day is September 17th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 18, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-18/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">3b8515250eb5cd7581237f6031a7d7aea2a4ef6f</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"In the first place it should be known that if a person is seeking God, his beloved is seeking him much more." <strong>St. John of the Cross</strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Marriage releases the flesh from its individual selfishness for the service of the family; the vow of chastity releases the flesh not only from the narrow and circumscribed family, where there can still be selfishness, but also for the service of that family that embraces all humanity. That is why the Church asks those who consecrate themselves to the redemption of the world to take a vow and to surrender all selfishness, that they may belong to no one family and yet belong to all. That is why in that larger family of the kingdom of God, the priest is called “Father” —because he has begotten children not in the flesh, but in the spirit.”<br/>
—Venerable Fulton Sheen, p. 117</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"Hark, your watchmen lift up their voice, together they sing for joy; for eye to eye they see the return of the Lord to Zion. Break forth together into singing, you waste places of Jerusalem; for the Lord has comforted his people, he has redeemed Jerusalem. The Lord has bared his holy arm before the eyes of all the nations; and all the ends of the earth shall see the salvation of our God." <strong>Isaiah 52:8-10</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Joseph of Cupertino" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4336.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Joseph of Cupertino</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Joseph of Cupertino (1603-1663) was the son of a poor Italian carpenter. His father died before he was born, leaving his mother destitute. As a result Joseph was underfed and often sick. He was an intellectually dull child who constantly found himself the worse off in every situation. He was awkward, absent-minded, unintelligent, and difficult to be around. Many people thought he was good for nothing–including his own mother, who treated him harshly and considered him a burden. Added to the scorn he received from everyone, at the age of eight he began receiving ecstatic visions for which he was also ridiculed. At the age of seventeen Joseph found work with the Capuchin Franciscan friars, eventually joining their order once they recognized his holiness beneath his irritating demeanor. His ecstasies became more pronounced, and he would often levitate or float as they happened. These ecstasies could be triggered easily through the mention of anything heavenly, or by any mortification. These occurrences became a spectacle and disturbance to others and caused Joseph much suffering; they were a cross he would bear his whole life. For example, as a priest he could not celebrate Mass publicly due to his distracting ecstasies. He was even reported to the Inquisition for fear he was involved in witchcraft. Yet St. Joseph lived a life of deep prayer and severe penance through continual fasting, subjecting himself every year to seven Lents of forty days each. Sometimes called “The Flying Saint,” St. Joseph of Cupertino is also the patron of air crews and aviators. His feast day is September 18th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 19, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-19/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">b1ad9ca35a31c50201b9940a39d45ff8c8ae78b0</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"The closer one approaches to God, the simpler one becomes." <strong>St. Teresa of Avila</strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“Meekness is spiritual; meekness is joy. And we should all strive to have in our hearts that joy that is contagiously cheerful. We need not think that we must be continually joking; nor should we believe that even-temperedness must express its happiness in laughter. We may and undoubtedly will have bothersome worries, but we can and should be even-tempered, retain our peace of heart, be meek in spite of them. We can at least bear with life’s small problems in such a way as not to allow them to rush upon others. Even temper is attractive, helps the community spirit, keeps down all that ends to anger for it seeks under varying circumstances to be pleasant, amiable, agreeable, mild, patient. It is, in fact, the practice of many virtues.”<br/>
—Matt Fradd, p.79</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"Thus says the Lord who made the earth, the Lord who formed it to establish it—the Lord is his name: Call to me and I will answer you, and will tell you great and hidden things which you have not known." <strong>Jeremiah 33: 2-3</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Januarius" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/3720.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Januarius</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p>St. Januarius (d. 305 A.D.), also known as San Gennaro, was the Bishop of Benevento, Italy. Little is known of his early life. He was arrested and imprisoned for his faith while visiting other Christians in jail during the persecution of Roman Emperor Diocletian. Many attempts were made to kill him, but one after another they failed. He was thrown into a fiery furnace, but he came out unscathed. He was then thrown to wild beasts in the amphitheater, but they did not attack. He was finally beheaded, and his blood was collected by Christians and kept in a sealed glass vial for veneration. The vial of blood is still kept today in the Naples cathedral, and it has continually demonstrated miraculous properties for which no scientific explanation has been offered. St. Januarius' blood liquefies and becomes fresh on particular occasions throughout the year, especially his feast day, for which the saint has become famous. This phenomenon has been occurring with regularity for centuries, and is one of the "blood miracles" that is historically well-documented among the relics of certain saints. He is the patron saint of blood banks and the city of Naples, Italy. St. Januarius's feast day is September 19th.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 20, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-20/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">50e29b67285d857e4cffd1c2e44bd4d4c0c042dc</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"We have received baptism, entrance into the Church, and the honor of being called Christians. Yet what good will this do us if we are Christians in name only and not in fact?" <strong>St. Andrew Kim Taegon </strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“The second stage of contemplation and the sixth of prayer is that of quiet. This is the union of the will with God, who, as highest Good, attracts it forcefully so that in Him alone it may find its rest. Infinite power, goodness, gentleness, and sweetness, with God’s gifts of fear, piety, fortitude, and wisdom, overwhelm it and at the same time take it captive, set it ablaze, fill it with caresses, and drawing it near…there the soul finds for a time every now and then—times that seem to it short however long they last—its full rest, its refreshment and strength, its peace and happiness.”<br/>
—J.G Arintero, O.P., p.44-45</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"Blessed are you when they insult you and persecute you and utter every kind of evil against you [falsely] because of me. Rejoice and be glad, for your reward will be great in heaven. Thus they persecuted the prophets who were before you." <strong>Matthew 5:11-12</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Andrew Kim Tae-gon" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4342.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Andrew Kim Tae-gon</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p> St. Andrew Kim Tae-gon (1821-1846) was born to a noble family in Korea, and was baptized at the age of 15 after his parents converted to the Catholic faith. Andrew's father, great-grandfather, and great-uncle were martyred during the government's staunch persecution against Christianity, leaving the remaining family in poverty. Andrew was later chosen to travel over 1,000 miles to the nearest seminary in China to be trained for the priesthood. He was ordained in Shanghai as the first native Korean priest in the Church's history of evangelizing in that country. He returned to Korea in secrecy to avoid detection by the authorities. Once back in his hometown, he worked to catechize the faithful until his bishop summoned him to Seoul to help smuggle French missionaries from China into Korea, with the aid of Chinese fishermen. During this operation he was caught and imprisoned by the border patrol, and charged as a traitor to his country. He was tortured and beheaded on September 16, 1846, at the age of 25. Pope John Paul II canonized Fr. Andrew Kim Tae-gon, along with 102 other Korean martyrs, on May 6, 1984. St. Andrew Kim Tae-gon is the patron saint of Korea. His feast day is celebrated on September 20th.  	 </p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item><item>
  <title>Morning Offering for September 21, 2025</title>
  <link>https://www.morningoffering.com/offering/09-21/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">c8688de8ef68ba7675eaa90b55b3c3ed5309bbe8</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
  <description><![CDATA[
<h2>The Morning Offering</h2>
<p>O Jesus, through the Immaculate Heart of Mary, I offer you my prayers, works, joys, and sufferings of this day for all the intentions of your Sacred Heart, in union with the Holy Sacrifice of the Mass throughout the world, for the salvation of souls, the reparation of sins, the reunion of all Christians, and in particular for the intentions of the Holy Father this month. Amen.</p>
<h2>Saint Quote</h2>
<section class="saint-quote" id="saint-quote"><blockquote>
"For me, prayer is a surge of the heart; it is a simple look turned toward heaven, it is a cry of recognition and of love, embracing both trial and joy." <strong>St. Therese of Lisieux</strong></blockquote></section>
<section id="meditation"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Today's</span> Meditation</h2><p>“There is no such thing as a dull, futile, or useless experience. Every sorrow loses its sting, because everything is an opportunity to glorify God. Saint Paul wrote, “For the sake of Christ, then, I am content with weaknesses, insults, hardships, persecutions, and calamities: for when I am weak, then I am strong” (2 Cor 12:10). Once you have learned to find contentment in adversity, all of life becomes changed with light and hope and joy.”<br/>
–J. Augustine Wetta, O.S.B, p. 103</p></section>
<section class="daily-verse" id="daily-verse"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Daily</span> Verse</h2><blockquote>
"As Jesus passed on from there, He saw a man called Matthew sitting at the tax office; and He said to him, “Follow me.” And he rose and followed Him." <strong>Matthew 9:9</strong></blockquote></section>
<h2>Saint of the Day</h2>
<img alt="St. Matthew" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4343.png" width="1"/>
<div class="col-lg-6"><h2 class="block-heading">St. Matthew</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Saint of the Day</h5><p> St. Matthew the Apostle (1st c.) was a Jew who also went by the name of Levi. He was from Galilee and served in Capernaum as a tax collector for Herod Antipas before becoming a disciple of Jesus. It was in the home of St. Matthew that Jesus dined with the "sinners and tax collectors."  Under Jesus' influence St. Matthew was led to repentance for the evil he had done as a tax-collector, a position despised by his fellow Jews. He repaid those he cheated four-fold, sold all his possessions, and followed Christ as one of the twelve Apostles. St. Matthew preached among the Jews for fifteen years following the Resurrection and Ascension of Jesus. He is the author of the Gospel that bears his name, which he wrote to convince the Jews that Jesus Christ was the Messiah promised to Israel. According to tradition, St. Matthew the Apostle brought the Gospel to Syria, Media, Persia, Parthia, and finished his preaching in Ethiopia with a martyr’s death. He is the patron of guards, bankers, accountants, security forces, and stock brokers. His feast day is September 21st.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQn8extGJkx1NvOzwvl1oXP19zKdpOwpF" target="_blank"><picture><source srcset="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/webp-express/webp-images/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg.webp" type="image/webp"/><img alt="Listen to The Saint of the Day Podcast" class="webpexpress-processed" src="https://www.morningoffering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/sotd-podcast-banner.jpg"/></picture></a></p></div>
<h2>Devotion of the Month</h2>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-lg-1"><h2 class="block-heading"><span>Month of </span> Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)</h2><h5 class="sub-header">Devotion of the Month</h5><p>The Church dedicates the month of September to Our Lady of Sorrows, also known as Mater Dolorosa (Mother of Sorrows). This devotion recalls the Blessed Virgin Mary’s spiritual martyrdom in virtue of her perfect union with the Passion of Christ. This was her role in salvation history, and what merited her place as the spiritual Mother of all Christians. This is symbolized by a single sword, or seven swords, piercing Mary's suffering heart, as foretold in Simeon's prophecy. Traditionally the Church meditates on the "Seven Sorrows" of our Blessed Mother: the prophecy of Simeon; the Holy Family's flight into Egypt; the loss of the Child Jesus for three days; the meeting of Mary and Jesus as he carried his cross; Jesus' crucifixion and death; Jesus' sacred body taken down from the cross; and Jesus' burial. The feast of Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa) is September 15th.</p>
</div>
<div class="col-md-7 col-lg-6 order-lg-2">
<img alt="Month of the Our Lady of Sorrows (Mater Dolorosa)" class="display-imagery" height="1" src="https://static.trinityroad.com/sites/cc/morning_offering/saints/4964.png" width="1"/></div>
<div class="col-lg-6 order-sm-1"><h2 class="block-heading">Daily Prayers</h2><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Dead</h3><p>In your hands, O Lord, we humbly entrust our brothers and sisters.<br/>
In this life you embraced them with your tender love;<br/>
deliver them now from every evil and bid them eternal rest.<br/>
The old order has passed away: welcome them into paradise,<br/>
where there will be no sorrow, no weeping or pain,<br/>
but fullness of peace and joy with your Son and the Holy<br/>
Spirit forever and ever. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer of Spiritual Communion</h3><p>My Jesus, I believe that You are present in the most Blessed Sacrament. I love You above all things and I desire to receive You into my soul. Since I cannot now receive You sacramentally, come at least spiritually into my heart. I embrace You as if You were already there, and unite myself wholly to You. Never permit me to be separated from You. Amen.</p><h3 class="sub-header">Prayer for the Holy Father</h3><p class="p1">Almighty and everlasting God, have mercy upon Thy servant, Pope Leo XIV, our Supreme Pontiff, and direct him, according to Thy loving kindness, in the way of eternal salvation; that, of Thy gift, he may ever desire that which is pleasing unto Thee and may accomplish it with all his might. Through Christ, Our Lord. Amen.<em> Our Father. Hail Mary.</em></p></div>
  ]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
